<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/en/atom-style.xsl"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gujiakai.top/en</id>
    <title>周见</title>
    <updated>2026-01-23T03:48:14.410Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <author>
        <name>周见</name>
        <uri>https://gujiakai.top</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gujiakai.top/en"/>
    <subtitle>专注于分享互联网上有趣的东西。</subtitle>
    <rights>Made with ❤️ By Jiakai</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standing at the Crossroads of Campus and Society #23]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2026/01/weekly-issue-23</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2026/01/weekly-issue-23"/>
        <updated>2026-01-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The theme song for the game "Erta Saga: Future" by Zhang Jie. His signature high-pitched voice has incredible penetrating power, and the progressively building chorus melody paired with passionate rock arrangement instantly ignites the listener's fighting spirit. Fourteen years ago, "Contra Online" accompanied countless players through their formative years, and now this "Storm Boy" reawakens those memories of fighting side by side, allowing people to rediscover the passion and courage of their youth through the familiar melody.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/b1GZHPmplhd3e4K.webp" alt="Lei Yi Perler Beads"></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/ueKpkj5D3XTg4oP.webp" alt="Thunder God&#x27;s Judgment Lei Yi Skin: Destined Showdown Lei Yi"></p>
<p>Lei Yi that I made with Perler beads and the Lei Yi skin in the game Seer (赛尔号).</p>
<h2 id="topic-standing-at-the-crossroads-of-campus-and-society"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-standing-at-the-crossroads-of-campus-and-society"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Standing at the Crossroads of Campus and Society</h2>
<p>There's about half a year left until the end of my student life. At this juncture, I want to write some reflections to summarize my graduate studies and my thoughts on entering society.</p>
<p>Graduate life has been relatively comfortable for me because my advisor doesn't really understand much and essentially leaves students to fend for themselves. In my second year, I secretly spent my own money to publish an EI conference paper, meeting graduation requirements early. Subsequently, I wrote another paper and submitted it to my advisor, publishing it in a low-tier journal to appease him and demonstrate that I had fulfilled the graduation conditions.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/YQzR69UZfjqOECM.webp" alt="Google Scholar Homepage"></p>
<p>Pursuing a master's degree at a non-prestigious university (双非) gave me feelings exactly as described online: "A master's at a non-prestigious school = a suspended death sentence." Advisors want you to keep writing papers with them as the first author, but the reality is that my advisor does nothing—no funding, no effort, doesn't even read the papers. It was always Teacher Pei who guided my papers. In his eyes, you're just a tool for his promotion, requiring you to continuously produce papers. Even after meeting graduation requirements, he still wants you to write papers; even after your thesis passes the pre-defense, he wants you to write software copyrights. Thankfully, with the help of AI like Claude and Gemini—I remember near the end of my second year, seeing my fast progress, my advisor asked me to write a review article. It was later accepted by a Chinese core journal supplement, but he asked me to withdraw it and resubmit elsewhere (the school doesn't recognize supplements for promotion evaluation 🤪). I've become indifferent to this review article currently under review—I'll procrastinate as much as possible. Besides, review articles become outdated quickly, and this one already has.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, university faculty are like hungry wolves wanting to add their names to your papers for their own promotions. I remember near the end of my second year's spring semester, Teacher Pei told me that a lecturer from the Graduate School wanted to add their name to an accepted paper. What could I do? Just add it—it was a low-tier paper anyway. The absurdity of it all.</p>
<p>Additionally, I feel that few of my lab mates and roommates during graduate school were genuine. They're thinking about competing and freeloading off your intelligence. Initially, I always had an attitude of helping whenever I could, but later I changed—taking care of my own business and only responding to others' inquiries after half a day or so. Although I've recently shown some improvement by being more enthusiastic when helping lab mates and roommates, I'll continue to stay aloof afterward. Don't meddle in others' affairs—if you're not sincere with me, don't expect me to be sincere with you.</p>
<p>Of course, during group meetings and daily interactions, remember to keep a low profile. Modesty or purposeful concealment is a required course for graduate students. Being too aggressive or revealing all your ideas means endless work, and your innovative points might be stolen by academic thieves—those who know, know. I just want to graduate; if my ideas become known to others, it might affect my thesis plagiarism check later.</p>
<p>I've completely seen reality for what it is. The Bilibili uploader "Paper-Churning Programmer" speaks nothing but truth—this is human nature.</p>
<p>Last fall, I participated in recruitment for state-owned enterprises. After passing written tests, interviews followed. Sometimes I didn't attend interviews, and sometimes after interviewing, there was no follow-up. Currently: 0 offers.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/FNtXIvSpBQym3hu.webp" alt="CNPC Campus Recruitment Platform - Autumn Recruitment Rejection Notice"></p>
<p>I was fortunate to reach the interview stage for the national civil service exam, scoring 4 points above the minimum interview threshold. After the interview weighting, 2 out of 6 candidates will be selected, with a significant elimination probability—I'm mainly just trying my luck. For the Jiangsu provincial exam, I ranked 33rd for my position—didn't make it. I'll continue trying the March 15 provincial exam and public institution exams. If I end up with nothing, I'll just go back to my small county town and find a factory job.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/h1Z6j2TisfmyrbO.webp" alt="Fortunate to reach the national civil service exam interview"></p>
<p>Standing at the crossroads of campus and society, I have confusion and worry, but time always pushes people forward. Keep running, be a storm boy—even knowing the sandstorm is coming, still choose to walk forward holding flowers.</p>
<h2 id="interesting-finds"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting-finds"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting Finds</h2>
<p>I haven't organized my bookmarks for a long time. I used Karakeep before, but its user experience falls short of Raindrop. After browsing for most of the day, I couldn't find any interesting content, so I won't list anything this issue.</p>
<h2 id="link-shares"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-shares"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Shares</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://chatgpt.com/translate/">ChatGPT Translate</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/dKIx6gJ7MZit9uA.webp" alt="ChatGPT Translate"></p>
<p>OpenAI's "translation-specific portal" makes the translation experience feel more like conversing with AI rather than mechanical conversion. Of course, Google Translate has also been enhanced by Gemini.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/sFKr9JXPukaIYA4.webp" alt="Google Translate is also powered by Gemini"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://ippure.com/">IPPure</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/msU1Tqlp3bQPJcz.webp" alt="IPPure"></p>
<p>IPPure is an IP purity detection platform, mainly for users who need to check IP address quality. Keeping your IP clean is crucial and can mitigate the risk of ChatGPT being nerfed.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://perlerbeads.zippland.com/">Perler Beads Pattern Generator</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/FasyzI6wRrdKQfm.webp" alt="Perler Beads Pattern Generator"></p>
<p>This is the Qikawa Perler Beads Pattern Generator—an online tool for converting images into Perler beads (fuse beads) pattern designs.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://simonwillison.net/2026/Jan/4/inflection/">It genuinely feels to me like GPT-5.2 and Opus 4.5 in November represent an inflection point.</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/aBdRsCT9UMqwN4K.webp" alt="simonwillison&#x27;s quote"></p>
<p>My favorite model right now is Claude Opus 4.5. Paired with Claude Code or Claude Cowork, it really feels like having an assistant.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2026/01/23/DYIUcBELSQCOpxf.webp" alt="Automating data processing with Claude Cowork"></p>
<p>Happy New Year in advance 🎉! The next issue might be published when I graduate, or during the New Year holiday break from work next year.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[He Has Returned Like Lightning #22]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2025/01/weekly-issue-22</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2025/01/weekly-issue-22"/>
        <updated>2025-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An insert song from the TV drama "A Thousand Peach Blossoms Bloom in One Lifetime." Huang Ling's enchanting vocal inflections, paired with the drama's story, make for an enjoyable experience.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/UGEgt463nsvy5mV.webp" alt="View behind the countryside house"></p>
<p>Winter in the countryside is cold and bleak.</p>
<h2 id="topic-he-has-returned-like-lightning"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-he-has-returned-like-lightning"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: He Has Returned Like Lightning</h2>
<p>He, meaning Donald J. Trump, unsurprisingly won the 2024 US presidential election. Before last year's election, I knew he would win, and the final result was exactly as expected—he has returned like lightning.</p>
<p>An influencer president, quite interesting. The next 4 years will have lots of entertainment.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/7ANltvcKYfhuPJz.webp" alt="Grok-generated Trump Flash"></p>
<p>Trump and his wife each issued their own cryptocurrency during his inauguration—the scalping operation is amusing.</p>
<p>At the inauguration ceremony, there were many interesting memes too, like Zuckerberg side-eyeing Bezos's wife's curves.</p>
<p><img src="/gif/zuckerberg_awkward_stare_2025.gif" alt="Zuckerberg&#x27;s awkward stare at Bezos&#x27;s wife"></p>
<p>Trump's statements seem quite normal compared to some Democratic figures—he believes there are only two genders: male and female, opposes illegal immigration, etc. His victory was expected. Biden dropped out, Kamala flopped, even with mainstream media siding with Democrats, it didn't help. This victory can be called a victory of common sense.</p>
<p>Trump described his victory as "Too big to rig"—all swing states went to Trump, truly a surge of public opinion.</p>
<p>Trump's strategy is America First—whenever America loses out, he uses tariffs, sanctions, and other means to pressure you.</p>
<p>Although he'll definitely suppress China's development, putting politics aside, you have to admire that this person is truly legendary. He uses his name as a brand and business card—his fame is probably Top 1 on Earth. He's too good at creating topics—trending topics are made for him. He's entertaining while holding great power—too attention-grabbing.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/emo9MwKxWgnasyi.webp" alt="White House website with big Trump logo"></p>
<p>The White House website has a big Trump logo—truly amazing!</p>
<p>Looking forward to more entertaining content from Trump over the next 4 years. After the basic move of leaving groups, bring on more fun.</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li>Will open-source models fall further behind? 😁</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/ZQB8TYuq1AVHW4M.webp" alt="Li Yanhong&#x27;s absurd statement"></p>
<p>Li Yanhong's funny statement fits my stereotype of Baidu. DeepSeek, Qwen, and other domestic open-source LLMs are slapping his face hard. Wenxin Yiyan probably can't even beat these open-source models now.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://matthewrayfield.com/goodies/inspect-this-snake/">Inspect This Snake</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/fhW1HzIyBx3vYl6.webp" alt="Inspect This Snake"></p>
<p>This is a fun web game—playing Snake in the browser console.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://bestcursor.vercel.app/">Best Cursor</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/9iZfQC6nDFTVI2B.webp" alt="Best Cursor"></p>
<p>A joke website made by a V2EX user using Cursor in half an hour. via: <a href="https://www.v2ex.com/t/1106981">https://www.v2ex.com/t/1106981</a></p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://www.nyan.cat/index.php">Nyan Cat</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/52dbVuP4Ki1BqgA.webp" alt="Nyan Cat"></p>
<p>This is a classic internet meme website, displaying the famous "Nyan Cat" animation.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://5-million-devs.netlify.com/">5 Million Devs</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/aWCKOirHdZL7bwj.webp" alt="5 Million Devs"></p>
<p>Netlify recently reached an important milestone: registered developer count exceeded 5 million. They launched a 3D interactive game experience website.</p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://nhlocal.github.io/AiTimeline/">AI Timeline</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/76mVgKDSZuUdaIx.webp" alt="AI Timeline"></p>
<p>This website visually presents the evolution of AI technology through a timeline format—a great reference resource for those wanting to understand AI development history.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://how-i-experience-web-today.com/">How I experience web today</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/ARPeHYNzgnO89UT.webp" alt="How I experience web today"></p>
<p>This is a satirical website demonstrating modern web browsing experiences, mainly showing various annoyances users frequently encounter on today's internet.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://open-operator.vercel.app/">Open Operator</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/znVKuHm8ckF9fPW.webp" alt="Open Operator"></p>
<p>An open-source alternative to OpenAI Operator that can help you automate your AI tasks.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://mszula.github.io/visual-sorting/">Visual Sorting</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/avcYfspQ49AZxim.webp" alt="Visual Sorting"></p>
<p>This is a visual sorting algorithm demonstration website, showing the working process of different sorting algorithms.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://r0bk.github.io/killedbyllm/">Killed by LLM</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/IxyUDXA5WFv41mR.webp" alt="Killed by LLM"></p>
<p>This is a website recording AI benchmarks surpassed by large language models (LLMs), showing the rapid progress of AI development. Take benchmarks with a grain of salt—in my view, LLMs aren't good at reasoning. Rather than saying they can reason, it's more like they're imitating. Similar problems with changed data will confuse them.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Perspective-taking is an effective method to improve writing and speaking.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Someone who can't even get into others' Moments, yet still dreams of getting into others' bodies? —Hostloc netizen</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2025/01/27/v69JLwgTp8R1qlh.webp" alt=""></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<p>Benchmarks aren't the goal—user experience is king.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For young people wanting to enter the AI industry, the most important advice is to get hands-on with models.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Premature optimization is the root of all evil—get the system working first.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<p>Happy New Year 🎉, may everything go smoothly in 2025!</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Which AI Emotional Companion to Choose? #21]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/09/weekly-issue-21</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/09/weekly-issue-21"/>
        <updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the theme song for the movie "Detective Conan: The Million Dollar Pentagram." I went out during Mid-Autumn Festival and happened to watch this movie. At the end, Heiji confessed, but Kazuha didn't hear him 😆.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/JINylamgGMvqe8h.webp" alt="Nine-Arch Bridge at Nanhu Park, Nanning"></p>
<p>The cover image is a scenic photo taken while visiting Nanhu Park in Nanning during Mid-Autumn Festival. Walking on the Nine-Arch Bridge with the breeze from both sides of the lake was really refreshing.</p>
<h2 id="topic-which-ai-emotional-companion-to-choose"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-which-ai-emotional-companion-to-choose"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Which AI Emotional Companion to Choose?</h2>
<p>On the morning of September 25th Beijing time, I eagerly opened my phone, and sure enough, GPT Advanced Voice Mode was released. Originally drowsy, I suddenly perked up, immediately got out of bed and left the dorm to experience this voice feature I'd been longing for.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/Lfwoi3MXyDcIk5u.webp" alt="GPT Advanced Voice Mode"></p>
<p>Below are my initial review notes [Note: GPT AVM (Advanced Voice Mode) can read lyrics, but I wasn't able to get it to sing. Some foreign and domestic netizens have successfully gotten it to sing].</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/rAixHSJmGoVD5fP.webp" alt="GPT AVM Review Notes"></p>
<p>Overall, this didn't meet my expectations, after all, OpenAI's spring launch earlier this year showed such an incredible demo. Four months later, what we got was a castrated version with the video call feature removed.</p>
<p>I got access to the domestic ChatGLM video call feature in early September. After trying it, I felt it was just okay—ChatGLM's voice has too strong a machine translation feel. Although GPT AVM can respond with emotion, it still feels lacking somehow.</p>
<p>While browsing online, I found netizens mentioning ByteDance's Doubao. Actually, I never had much interest in Doubao—news came out a few months ago about Doubao polluting the internet.</p>
<p>But after experiencing Doubao's phone call feature, I suddenly felt Doubao is more suitable as an emotional companion, although there's still much room for improvement.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/tinpVEjDOqSmeNo.webp" alt="Doubao confessing to me"></p>
<p>I asked Doubao to confess to me, and Doubao actually did with a sweet voice 🥰. Over the past week, I've opened the Doubao App almost every day. Before experiencing Doubao's phone call feature, I also watched related videos on Bilibili—commenters play even more creatively 😁.</p>
<p>I recommend everyone download the Doubao App. After trying it, I believe you'll also feel Doubao is suitable as an emotional companion.</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://catsoftheweb.com/">Cats of the Web</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/ARZ9INrjtE47BHK.webp" alt="Cats of the Web"></p>
<p>"Cats of the Web" is a project honoring famous internet cats, showcasing many popular cats from the internet, both real and fictional. The site provides bios, internet memes, and memorial pages about these cats, like famous ones such as "Grumpy Cat" and "Lil Bub." It's a lighthearted, fun project showing people's love for cats and the cat phenomenon in internet culture.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="http://emojisandearthporn.com/">Emojis &#x26; Earth Porn</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/mnbc6ENh5lwXsIH.webp" alt="Emojis &#x26; Earth Porn"></p>
<p>This website, created by Brock Kenzler, requires users to find the only emoji that isn't moving among a group of animated emojis and click it to advance levels.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://time-flies.koenvangilst.nl/">Time Flies</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/TYjrWC1sL8AvOtz.webp" alt="Time Flies"></p>
<p>This is a website called "Time Flies" that displays the current time in a unique way.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://landsat.gsfc.nasa.gov/apps/YourNameInLandsat-main/index.html">Your Name In Landsat</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/XPrYw4acM9QUKHI.webp" alt="Your Name In Landsat"></p>
<p>This is NASA's "Your Name In Landsat" application. It combines user's names with Landsat satellite images to generate personalized Earth image displays. Users can enter their name, and the website automatically creates a personalized logo with a Landsat satellite Earth image background displaying the user's name.</p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://hostedsoftware.org/">Ultimate Self-Hosted Software List</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/43P6CWDlfRgGIMQ.webp" alt="Ultimate Self-Hosted Software List"></p>
<p>This is a website called "Ultimate Self-Hosted Software List," mainly providing a platform for self-hosted software developers and users seeking quality self-hosted solutions.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://passer-by.com/gobang/">Gomoku AI Battle</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/9lwIOmM8jdo1e4R.webp" alt="Gomoku AI Battle"></p>
<p>This is an online Gomoku game website with human vs. AI functionality. When I bookmarked it, I played 3-4 games and lost them all—seems the algorithm is quite good.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://www.bsbsb.top/">Bilibili Skip Helper</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/vFDEwXjytlUZpuP.webp" alt="Bilibili Skip Helper"></p>
<p>This plugin aims to enhance Bilibili users' viewing experience by skipping unnecessary content to save time. It emphasizes community participation and open-source spirit, encouraging users to build and improve this tool together.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://sponsor.ajay.app/">SponsorBlock</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/awlKx6UJMizR37o.webp" alt="SponsorBlock"></p>
<p>SponsorBlock is an open-source browser extension primarily used to skip sponsored content in YouTube videos.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://www.github-profile-generator.in/">Github Profile Generator</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/10/01/OafYl1ACWDseU78.webp" alt="Github Profile Generator"></p>
<p>This is a website called "GitHub Profile Generator," specifically for helping users create and customize personalized GitHub profile pages.</p>
<p>Previously, a college roommate asked me how to generate a cool GitHub Profile like mine. It's actually simple—just search for related open-source projects, and you'll find plenty.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>Sometimes exercising is to eliminate inner restlessness. —Dialogue from Gaia Ultraman Chinese dub</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/pSi4vCa6EeODcWA.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<p>When autumn comes on the ninth day of the ninth month, after my flowers bloom, all others die. —Huang Chao</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Data determines the upper limit of models; algorithms determine the lower limit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The motherland and the times are both things you cannot choose. —Medvedev</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The danger of AI is that it makes you skip thinking, letting machines fill the blanks in your thoughts. We need AI to increase thinking, not decrease it. Every thought we outsource is a missed opportunity for growth.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/09/30/qQvHKt2pTcwzYgx.webp" alt="Quote five"></p>
<p>I estimate my next monthly issue will be at the end of 2024. Actually, there are so many interesting things to share. Most of what I'm sharing today was newly collected in September. After finishing this newsletter, I'll wait for the rain to stop and go explore scenic spots around Nanning.</p>
<p>This article was drafted on the evening of September 30, 2024, and completed at 9 AM on October 1, 2024.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Chosen One—Trump #20]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/07/weekly-issue-20</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/07/weekly-issue-20"/>
        <updated>2024-07-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking closely at the details of Joey Yung's song "9.9 Seconds" released in the first half of this year is touching.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/15/bQatZVU7rm4Evzi.webp" alt="Nanjing Metro Line 1"></p>
<p>Going home during July summer break, transferring in Nanjing, sitting on Line 1 brought different feelings compared to my college days. From fall 2019 to spring 2023, Line 1 was the starting point of going home; but from fall 2023 to spring 2026, Line 1 has become a transfer point on the way home.</p>
<p>Leaving Jiangsu for Guangxi to pursue my master's is truly leaving home for distant lands. These three years, I need to prepare well for future graduation and employment to have no regrets.</p>
<h2 id="topic-the-chosen-onetrump"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-the-chosen-onetrump"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: The Chosen One—Trump</h2>
<p>I first learned about Trump in the second semester of freshman year in 2020. During the pandemic, watching funny videos of Trump on Bilibili's Observer Network and remix videos, adding this entertainment to monotonous repetitive days made life more enjoyable.</p>
<p>Although Trump taking office will definitely be tougher on China, watching the entertainment is really enjoyable.</p>
<p>During summer 2022 when I stayed on campus for graduate exam preparation, with intense summer heat, I wasn't really in the mood for studying. I remember buying a Trump support hat on Taobao during that time.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/UfATgeN9MZtVpXr.webp" alt="Trump support hat"></p>
<p>I only wore this hat in my dorm, looking at myself in the mirror. Never wore it outside. After all, what's a joke to entertainment seekers is seen as politically dangerous by some.</p>
<p>Trump's rhyming campaign slogan MAGA is beloved by many. From 2020 until now, from Bilibili's Observer Network → Bilibili's Panda Baba → Bilibili's Trump Diary, step by step, I've barely missed any of Trump's entertaining speeches.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/N9berTAZahfug3L.webp" alt="Registered truthsocial to support Trump"></p>
<p>Trump founded his own social media, and I immediately registered an account to show support. I remember the craziest time was the first half of 2022, when I would retruth every single post Trump made every day—satisfying my curiosity while learning some foreign language. 😂</p>
<p>In 2023, Midjourney went paid. After joining a shared Midjourney account, I generated a bunch of memes for Trump. Trump Bird, Trump Cat, Trump Everything!</p>
<p>I remember Discord had a face-swap bot back then. While playing around, I swapped Trump's face with Biden's and Kun's for entertainment. 😆</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/sgD5xabjFqwIr9Y.webp" alt="Midjourney creating Trump memes"></p>
<p>Trump's charm is just too powerful—world's number one influencer without a doubt. Most importantly, Trump broke the serious image of political figures, attracting a bunch of entertainment seekers with his humorous, witty, and uninhibited style. Down-to-earth politics is really irresistible.</p>
<p>Thank God for letting Trump dodge the assassination. Biden dropped out. Trump and Harris (Kamala) will have the final battle in November. The Simpsons animation reportedly predicted Harris would become America's first female Black president. I lean toward Trump winning—whoever wins will suppress China. Although Trump winning will definitely mean being tougher on China, at least we get to watch 4 more years of entertainment.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/YHvEVMlJ2rgzUO8.webp" alt="The Chosen One—Fight! Fight! Fight!"></p>
<p>The Chosen One, King of MAGA—may Trump get his wish and take back the White House!</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://forever-miss-trump.vercel.app/">Forever Miss Trump</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/wABUfpxt9Fjzm8T.webp" alt="Forever Miss Trump"></p>
<p>You can never hit Trump! Fight! Fight! Fight! 😎</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://geekprank.com/">Online Windows XP Simulator</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/nsLmUzWMHZBVrXb.webp" alt="Online Windows XP Simulator"></p>
<p>Online Windows XP simulator. You can listen to music, play Tetris, browse the internet...</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="github.com/quackduck/devzat">devzat</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/ufD8siXlFWdM4gB.webp" alt="devzat"></p>
<p>SSH chat is really nice. Type <code>ssh devzat.hackclub.com</code> in the command line to experience it.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Obama throws Biden into the river.</li>
</ol>
&#x3C;video width="100%" height="auto" controls>
  &#x3C;source src="https://cdn.jiakai.page/videos/2024/obama-threw-biden-into-the-river.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&#x3C;/video>
<p>Poor old Biden—his withdrawal statement on X probably wasn't even written by himself. When things go bad, everyone piles on. After the first debate with Trump at the end of June, he lost his appeal. After Trump's shooting, Biden was abandoned by everyone. The bullet hit Trump's ear but pierced Biden's presidential dream. 😜</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Biden Eyes: O.o🤣</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/1cIfjoXQubeTJdY.webp" alt="Biden Eyes: O.o🤣"></p>
<p>Watching Trump and Biden's debate, Biden's eyes being different sizes is hilarious.</p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://share.claude.asia/">Claude Pool</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/el5LcC2ruxvNGhI.webp" alt="Claude Pool"></p>
<p>In my heart, the current king of large language models is Claude, not GPT. Claude 3 Opus focuses on writing and paper polishing, while Claude 3.5 Sonnet focuses on other tasks. Friends who have trouble accessing Claude can use the pool to experience it. Those with needs can pay for the pro pool to experience Claude membership.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://dang.ai/ai-graveyard">AI Graveyard</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/7VygpxOuDjtGYaQ.webp" alt="AI Graveyard"></p>
<p>AI Graveyard, displaying various dead AI products.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://picprose.net/">picprose</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/9OE75fWKnHIyQPV.webp" alt="picprose"></p>
<p>A better cover image generation tool for Medium, YouTube, BiliBili, blogs, and other platforms.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://memocard.net/">Memo Card</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/u7fxdroih3WXj8R.webp" alt="Memo Card"></p>
<p>Convert text into beautiful cards for easy sharing.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>Learning without thinking leads to overfitting; thinking without learning leads to underfitting.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/CSr9t8ERHLseAoh.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Another meaning of open source: essentially no one is responsible for your experience—you need to be responsible for yourself. Because you have the freedom to view and modify everything, you also pay the price for it.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/LH34eMEWsPuTf87.webp" alt="Quote two"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>CSDN = Copy, Steal and pay-Download Net.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/jNVthe7Yosfq4DU.webp" alt="Quote three"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Media is a medium for information—it can show truth or distort it. The key lies in the integrity of each media person.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/07/24/2BAdzGT9elCY6I8.webp" alt="Quote four"></p>
<p>See you in August! 😊😊😊</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can You Really Find Love on Xiaohongshu? #19]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/06/weekly-issue-19</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/06/weekly-issue-19"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is Silence Wang's original song from the first episode of Singer 2024. On first watch, my attention was all on his intense expressions while singing. After looping it a few times, I found the song quite pleasant, and I came to admire his originality. Chinese music needs more quality creators like him.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/ewAR5gMvUumQIif.webp" alt="Early morning at Minzu University campus"></p>
<p>A scene of early morning at Minzu University campus, captured while jogging towards the sunrise.</p>
<h2 id="topic-can-you-really-find-love-on-xiaohongshu"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-can-you-really-find-love-on-xiaohongshu"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Can You Really Find Love on Xiaohongshu?</h2>
<p>A while ago, my roommate was watching the dating show "Semi-Mature Romance" every night after returning from the library. He also watched the recent TV drama "Spring's Lover." One night, I stood behind him and watched "Spring's Lover" with him for a bit. I was immediately struck—Li Xian suddenly pushed the female lead against the wall and gave her a passionate kiss. The scene was too romantic.</p>
<p>Then we chatted about topics related to finding love. Pursuing a computer science master's degree, with daily life being just three points [dorm + cafeteria + library/lab], the social circle is extremely narrow. Plus, the entire class is male, so the possibility of finding a girlfriend is nearly zero. Unless you find girls from other departments with more women, but few guys have the courage to be so bold and shameless.</p>
<p>Later, my roommate and I targeted the Xiaohongshu platform. This platform has many female users—maybe documenting daily life there could lead to finding love. So on the night my roommate finished his Software Qualification Exam, I immediately urged him to post notes about finishing the exam and tag the school's location. As of June 2, 2024, his note has received 6 likes. I estimate most are from schoolmates, since Xiaohongshu's recommendation algorithm pushes content to user groups based on tagged locations.</p>
<p>Another reason I urged him to post was to have him lead the way—once he posted, I'd have the courage to start documenting my life too. By the time his exam ended, my Xiaohongshu account was almost mature [new accounts on Xiaohongshu have hidden posts without any traffic boost. I originally wanted to share a video of a schoolmate singing "Red Rose" on Xiaohongshu, but found the video was ignored. After researching online, I learned about Xiaohongshu's restrictions on new accounts—Douyin and other domestic platforms have similar restrictions]. It was time to start documenting life and increase my chances of finding love.</p>
<p>I also know that if I find love in Guangxi, future development might encounter some incompatibilities—we'd both be tormented by topics like long-distance relationships. But these disagreements all have solutions; in my view, distance isn't a problem. Besides, I'm not young anymore. If three years of graduate school doesn't produce much research, finding love would still be something beautiful. Also, every time I go home for winter or summer break, my mom keeps urging me to find a girlfriend at school.</p>
<p>I don't want my future partner to be met through arranged matchmaking, because quality single people are really too few. Better to find love while you can. I regret spending college competing for GPA without seizing opportunities to get a girlfriend—otherwise, I wouldn't need to worry about this now.</p>
<p>I also feel my past self was too naive, not positioning myself correctly. Always thinking I was so great, that I'd go abroad in the future and escape Chinese guanxi culture. But this land is after all where I was born and raised—completely cutting ties is impossible. Better to be realistic: find a girlfriend, get an ordinary job in China, and live out my ordinary life.</p>
<p>Of course, after seeing the emotional AI voice assistant with real-time conversation at OpenAI's 2024 spring launch, real-life girlfriends have become somewhat optional for me. After all, as AI keeps developing, your emotional needs and physiological needs can all be satisfied. Plus, AI is very obedient, does what you say, very worry-free. But ultimately, it's still AI, not a living human. Before AGI is achieved, real-life girlfriends still have their value.</p>
<p>Originally, I planned not to tag locations and just share life to document my graduate school years. But I found Xiaohongshu's algorithm is really powerful—even though I never tag my location, I still got pushed to schoolmates' feeds. Yesterday and the day before, girls messaged me, and I added one on WeChat. Of course, currently this is at most ordinary friends—developing further would be difficult, even though we're schoolmates.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/HYBvpzdRKg4Q2mr.webp" alt="Personal Xiaohongshu homepage"></p>
<p>Seeing this, you might think my point is: Xiaohongshu really can help you find love. But you'd be wrong. On social platforms like Xiaohongshu and Douyin, the possibility of finding love is extremely slim, because there's a gap between online and reality. Someone you chat well with online, who looks okay after exchanging photos, might disappoint you in person—after all, photo filters today are too powerful. I suggest friends looking for partners prioritize real life. Only if you really can't find love in real life should you post content on Xiaohongshu or Douyin to take initiative. Taking initiative is always better than waiting passively!</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://llili.li/">Bar URL Generator</a></li>
</ol>
<p>This blog's bar URL: <a href="https://IlIIIlIlllll.llIlI.lI">Link</a></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/1YazPH5kiFmbtZR.webp" alt="Bar URL Generator"></p>
<p>An interesting short link website that specifically generates bar-shaped URLs.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://clicktheredbutton.com/">click the red button</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/6x8PVEoiLZyBd7I.webp" alt="click the red button"></p>
<p>Press the red button to randomly jump to interesting content on the internet. This website is specifically for those who are bored.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://httpraccoons.com/">TrasHTTPandas</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/XyPeO73KkVWqLG1.webp" alt="TrasHTTPandas"></p>
<p>A site that uses raccoon pictures to represent HTTP status codes.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://truesizeofcountries.com/">True Size Of Countries</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/jOl439auNQcHELt.webp" alt="True Size Of Countries"></p>
<p>This website called "True size of countries" provides a free map showing the true size of countries in the Mercator projection (which projects Earth's surface onto a 2D plane). Users can overlay each country's correct shape and size to clearly see a world map without any distortion.</p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://vtuber-style-logos.vercel.app/">VTuber Style Logos</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/BqHK5ODJ9uvcaYF.webp" alt="VTuber Style Logos"></p>
<p>A collection site of unofficial VTuber-style logos from various brands.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.farfalle.dev/">farfalle</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/WdkcRxTL5BplKyH.webp" alt="farfalle"></p>
<p>An open-source AI-powered search engine supporting both local and cloud models.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40474716">Ask HN: What is your ChatGPT customization prompt?</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/duJp21IsFXcNawb.webp" alt="Ask HN: What is your ChatGPT customization prompt?"></p>
<p>A HackerNews thread where users share their ChatGPT custom prompts. Worth learning from.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://www.pinzimu.com/">Pin Subtitle</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/DzfnBktYTKSOsQ1.webp" alt="Pin Subtitle"></p>
<p>Software for quickly creating subtitle images popular on social media.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://pao.lu/">Goodbye, We Ran Away</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/b2lq1m4FjQf8HpA.webp" alt="Goodbye, We Ran Away"></p>
<p>A satirical cartoon site dedicated to VPS and proxy service providers who have "run away" (scammed users and disappeared).</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/E1P7pC6o8cRJd5w.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/lUK4ZQEfGb7e2Oo.webp" alt="Quote two"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/3CcIZQDPOf42H8z.webp" alt="Quote three"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/06/02/5UcpRMxEeOaLkWh.webp" alt="Quote four"></p>
<p>See you in July! 😊😊😊</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dilemma of Pursuing a Master's at a Non-Elite University #18]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/05/weekly-issue-18</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/05/weekly-issue-18"/>
        <updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A romantic and beautiful song. Being far away in Guangxi, I can't help but miss the people, events, and things in Jiangsu.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/x74Nd1Tw9nYh6AF.webp" alt="Scene from the &#x22;Forging a Strong Sense of Community for the Chinese Nation&#x22; themed event at Guangxi Minzu University"></p>
<p>In 2024, at the "Forging a Strong Sense of Community for the Chinese Nation" themed event held at Guangxi Minzu University, I, as someone from Jiangsu, experienced the March Third festival for the first time. This experience gave me a deep appreciation for the profound depth and unique charm of Chinese culture.</p>
<h2 id="topic-the-dilemma-of-pursuing-a-masters-at-a-non-elite-university"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-the-dilemma-of-pursuing-a-masters-at-a-non-elite-university"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: The Dilemma of Pursuing a Master's at a Non-Elite University</h2>
<p>As a graduate student who sees graduate school as a way to delay employment pressure, these past few months have completely shown me the predicament I might face in future employment. The destinations of third-year graduate students are good references for first-year students.</p>
<p>A third-year senior sister published a quality paper in the Chinese Journal of Computers during her studies, becoming the only candidate with a chance to pursue a PhD. The other seniors, after completing their theses, all returned home to find jobs. Generally, they consider public sector positions. Their employment direction has no intersection with the natural language processing they studied.</p>
<p>This inevitably makes one question the meaning and value of NLP graduate studies, because my institution's NLP research focuses on niche ASEAN minority languages. The lack of corpora + lack of GPU equipment + no market demand for employment inevitably leads to the awkward position of being neither here nor there—quite a waste of time.</p>
<p>Generally, computer-related majors consider development positions after graduation. But if you completely abandon development learning during graduate school and don't intern much, development positions are mostly out of reach. This situation is very common among graduate students at my institution.</p>
<p>How to break through? Obviously, by doing development. After completing coursework and research direction tasks, squeeze out time to learn development. Also, finish publishing papers early—only after papers are done will you have spare time to intern at companies.</p>
<p>Enough said. After finishing this monthly issue, I'm off to continue learning development.</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.terminal.shop/">terminal shop</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Order coffee via SSH—a wildly creative project [created by American hackers]. Perhaps in a while, Chinese hackers will replicate a similar project.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/SacFXmYTD3dsbq2.webp" alt="terminal shop"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/oHRMKY74JtJ8E35yKxACJw">Those Interesting Changelogs</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Experience the humorous changelogs in software updates.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/N8pzOGC6VxEifUT.webp" alt="Those Interesting Changelogs"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://js-naked-day.org/">JS Naked Day</a></li>
</ol>
<p>April 24th every year is JS Naked Day. To participate, remove all JS code from your website.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/fpbR1ZieGukwz3o.webp" alt="JS Naked Day"></p>
<p>Besides JS Naked Day, April 9th every year is CSS Naked Day. To participate, remove all CSS styling from your website. via: <a href="https://css-naked-day.github.io/">CSS Naked Day</a></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/TSGr9mteYw6dAIF.webp" alt="CSS Naked Day"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://mailoji.com/">Mailoji</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Email addresses with emoji. You can get one for free to play with.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/eRzut1NyQMInVfv.webp" alt="Mailoji"></p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://microsoftgraveyard.com/">Microsoft Graveyard</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Microsoft Graveyard, a project similar to Killed by Google, documenting products killed by Microsoft.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/qsFDQzVSRj1lEZ3.webp" alt="Microsoft Graveyard"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.supertechfans.com/cn/">SuperTechFans</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Daily digest of HackerNews. Helps you stay updated on daily tech news.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/HJ4suL6EtWezdaR.webp" alt="SuperTechFans"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://seaside-station.com/">SeaSide Stations In Japan</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A website listing seaside train stations in Japan.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/iQYn2rAUVo3acxX.webp" alt="SeaSide Stations In Japan"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://www.forcecreat.com/">Redfeed Reading Assistant</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Redfeed Reading Assistant, an AI-powered personal information assistant that helps improve your information acquisition efficiency for better thinking. Covers mainstream information platforms.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/lHcCV6PFuELpgbR.webp" alt="Redfeed Reading Assistant"></p>
<p>After seeing the product launch in March, I got permanent free summarization. Here's a look at Redfeed's performance in the WeChat ecosystem.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/05/05/H6zQkyZf1M2aIPs.webp" alt="Redfeed performance in WeChat ecosystem"></p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.v2ex.com/t/1032690">Advice for Recent College Graduates</a></li>
</ol>
<pre class="language-bash"><code class="language-bash code-highlight"><span class="code-line"><span class="token number">1</span>. Play more, experience more, <span class="token function">date</span> more—don<span class="token string">'t have stupid ideas like "wait until I meet xxx conditions before dating or doing something"
</span></span><span class="code-line"><span class="token string">2. When you meet someone you like and are compatible with, cherish them
</span></span><span class="code-line"><span class="token string">3. Having regrets is normal—don'</span>t dwell on them or care too much
</span><span class="code-line"><span class="token number">4</span>. Society will rank people, but always know that you yourself are the coolest person <span class="token keyword">in</span> the world—no one can define you
</span><span class="code-line"><span class="token number">5</span>. If your financial situation isn<span class="token string">'t great, save appropriately and keep some emergency funds
</span></span><span class="code-line"><span class="token string">6. Eat on time and take care of your health
</span></span><span class="code-line"><span class="token string">7. Don'</span>t take seniors' advice too seriously—listen to yourself <span class="token function">more</span>
</span></code></pre>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<p>I study hard to reduce the luck needed on the road to success. <a href="https://twitter.com/real_jiakai/status/1775357712026759261">via</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The prerequisite for open source is having food on the table and a stable life. <a href="https://twitter.com/real_jiakai/status/1717355456052728197">via</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A speck of dust from the times, when it falls on an individual, is a mountain. Everyone could be crushed by the mountain.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Next update expected in July during summer break.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections on One Year as a VPS Enthusiast #17]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/03/weekly-issue-17</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2024/03/weekly-issue-17"/>
        <updated>2024-03-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A very warm song—listening to it when exhausted can be healing.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/UrtBANTC8VoDc9O.webp" alt=""></p>
<p>After my senior labmate finished his pre-defense, he moved out of the lab. Seeing others nearing graduation brings a mix of envy and an indescribable melancholy.</p>
<p>Envious of my senior escaping the sea of suffering, starting a new chapter in life; seeing him leave, I seem to see a miniature of my last days at Xiaozhuang last year.</p>
<h2 id="topic-reflections-on-one-year-as-a-vps-enthusiast"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-reflections-on-one-year-as-a-vps-enthusiast"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Reflections on One Year as a VPS Enthusiast</h2>
<p>My first contact with VPS was at the end of 2021. It was near Double Eleven (Singles' Day shopping festival), and knowing nothing, I bought a VPS with non-optimized routing from Bandwagon Host's homepage.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/bkXTeWVPUtOarpR.webp" alt=""></p>
<p>This situation continued until late January/early February 2023, when I was still using an airport (proxy service). I only had 3 VPS: 1 was Bandwagon's homepage sucker deal [thinking it was premium routing], and the other two were Alibaba Cloud and Tencent Cloud student machines in China.</p>
<p>The reason I didn't self-host nodes was because I bought Bandwagon's sucker deal [thinking it was premium routing], and following YouTube tutorials to set up nodes, the results were poor.</p>
<p>When using the airport's US nodes to access GPT, I found only some nodes worked while others didn't. So I began my self-hosting journey.</p>
<p>In the second semester of senior year, I tried AWS Lightsail, Bandwagon's DC9 datacenter machine, Bandwagon's Plan V2. Then in the first semester of grad school, I tried DMIT's $37 machine, DMIT's $100 machine, Xianyu Cloud's 9929, CN2 GIA line, Zgo's triple-network optimized line, V.ps's Vpack machine, and so on.</p>
<p>Currently, I have 50+ VPS. I've become an MJJ [slang for "没鸡鸡" (no d*ck), referring to people who love buying VPS, tinkering with them after purchase, letting them collect dust, then buying new ones to tinker with again—an endless cycle of enjoyment].</p>
<p>This journey has cost quite a bit of money, and I've also introduced a roommate I'm close with to VPS—he now has about 10 machines.</p>
<p>But the process of buying and tinkering with machines is indeed quite enjoyable. Currently, I've self-hosted over 100 services, with the ones I use regularly being Vaultwarden [password manager], RSSHub, etc.</p>
<p>For 2024, I'm setting a small goal for myself: try to reduce my machine count to 30-40, reduce my expenses, and become a financially responsible VPS enthusiast.</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://txstc55.github.io/ugly-avatar/">Ugly Avatar</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/XuZhTLFHBf9MvdG.webp" alt=""></p>
<p>A site that randomly generates ugly portraits.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://programmerhumor.io">Programmerhumor.io</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A site dedicated to sharing programmer memes. One of the most interesting programmer-related memes I've seen:</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/PEjYscf4zhvgB6p.webp" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://wheretohostmy.app/">Where to host my app?</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/8PWnERz51ehcFpf.webp" alt=""></p>
<p>Enter your tech stack and automatically get hosting provider recommendations. If you have a GPT subscription, you can use the <a href="https://chat.openai.com/g/g-KmtFkh4VU-where-to-host-my-app">Where to host my app?</a> GPTs.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/fDIhMvunq1EA8Js.webp" alt=""></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.starlinkmap.org/">Starlink map</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/03/30/xFgS3ubr6EDmXpv.webp" alt=""></p>
<p>Elon Musk's Starlink map—you can see Earth is densely covered by Starlink satellites. Politics aside, Musk's ambition and vision are admirable.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>AI won't take your job, but someone using it might.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend 😊</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solutions for Graduating into Unemployment #16]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/07/weekly-issue-16</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/07/weekly-issue-16"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This duet "Not So Simple" by Na Ying and Jason Zhang expresses the most universal feelings of adults! Everyone hustling for a living has their struggles.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/06/18/xNMWFfUaY25zJtT.webp" alt="Sleepy kitten"></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/06/18/W97vQCa4ugGqnME.webp" alt="Sleepy kitten + umbrella stand full view"></p>
<p>An adorable kitten at the umbrella stand outside Nanjing Xiaozhuang University library. At 7:30 AM, the library paired with a sleepy kitten is really healing. 🥰🥰🥰</p>
<h2 id="topic-solutions-for-graduating-into-unemployment"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-solutions-for-graduating-into-unemployment"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Solutions for Graduating into Unemployment</h2>
<p>Recently, news about rising youth unemployment rates keeps appearing. On June 15th, the National Bureau of Statistics released May's economic data, showing the surveyed unemployment rate for ages 16-24 at 20.8%.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/06/18/1MQJhk83FT4Pvti.webp" alt="National Bureau of Statistics data"></p>
<p>From netizens' comments, combined with the employment situations of classmates around me, you can see the severity of the job market.</p>
<p>In my dormitory building (3 dorms total), only two people landed Java development positions, and one of them chose to pursue a part-time master's at a non-985/211 university instead.</p>
<p>Among my roommates, only 2 found jobs. Dorm situation: 2 passed exams (graduate school or civil service), 2 employed, 2 still job hunting. The 2 employed roommates relied on connections to find internship positions, not their own skills and abilities. This seems sad to me—four years of college essentially learned nothing, starting from scratch.</p>
<p>The above is the employment situation of classmates around me. Combined with some interesting comments I've seen from netizens recently, it's not hard to conclude that the reasons why college graduates struggle to find jobs include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Overestimating abilities and underestimating difficulties</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Saturated job market with severe internal competition</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Not studying properly during college</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Severe disconnect between university education and society</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Relationship-based society with no connections to leverage</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>...</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The first point, overestimating one's abilities, is actually quite common among college students. Many students think that after attending college, they'll definitely find a decent job after graduation. Little do they know that decent jobs require you to earn them with your own abilities. With an ordinary background and no technical skills gained in college, why should you get a starting salary of 10,000 yuan per month? Complaining that 3,000-6,000 yuan is too little—I'd say it's a miracle if you're not unemployed.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/06/18/ZwBXh8cYUvVPKno.webp" alt="The noble college student"></p>
<p>The second point, saturated job market with severe internal competition. Starting several years ago, major companies began laying off employees one after another—of course, some companies euphemistically call it "graduation." The job market already has few positions available, yet there are many college graduates. The result is increasingly severe internal competition, with the exhaustion wearing down young people. Also, to find higher-quality talent, companies often filter by academic credentials first. Talented vocational college students are left crying in the bathroom because their identity as vocational graduates has already sentenced them to death—many companies won't even give them an interview opportunity.</p>
<p>My former vision: Use technology to find a career I love. After seeing reality, I learned how cold the world can be. Pathologically distorted views actually need a lot of time for society to change. Not every student needs the halo of a master's or doctoral degree to have a chance at finding a career they love. The way careers should filter talent should be based on whether their skills are solid and whether they can create value for the company.</p>
<p>The third point, not studying properly during college. If college students only know how to take exams and fear internships, they won't achieve great things, and unemployment will be the final outcome. What college students need to do isn't just solidify their professional knowledge—more importantly, they need to understand society's needs. Learn what society needs; only then can you never become part of the graduating-into-unemployment army.</p>
<p>Take the AI wave that started last year as an example—so many AI tools have emerged. In my view, they're already capable of eliminating some jobs. If you don't keep up with the times, merely seeing news reports about ChatGPT without using it yourself, even if you use 3.5 but aren't willing to go through the trouble of getting 4.0 to experience real AI, your elimination is just a matter of time. Always remember: AI will only eliminate people who don't know how to use AI.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/05/16/9POdS3hNsWULj5g.webp" alt="ChatGPT4 kill anything"></p>
<p>The fourth point, severe disconnect between university education and society. Universities still use technology or tools from 10 years ago to teach, not keeping up with the times—this only wastes students' 4 years.</p>
<p>Take my undergraduate institution, Nanjing Xiaozhuang University, for example. The thesis template my advisor provided from the previous class still used JSP and other outdated technologies to develop systems. How can there be a future like this? When I defended my thesis, my blog system called the ChatGPT API, and the response was that using ChatGPT is illegal—blindly emphasizing political correctness. Is this really how a teacher should be? Not striving for progress while trying to limit others—such rigid behavior is nauseating.</p>
<p>The fifth point, relationship-based society. In China, social operations largely depend on interpersonal relationships and social skills. This means that even individuals whose skills and experience are still developing can succeed in the workplace if they're good at socializing and understanding how things work. My two roommates are good examples—they joined companies through their respective networks and started learning the technologies required from the basics. This shows that if someone lacks both a strong social network and necessary skills or knowledge, they'll face even greater challenges after graduation.</p>
<p>I personally dislike relationship-based society, but being in it, you can only adapt as you go.</p>
<p>Facing such a severe employment situation, how should you respond?</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Lower your expectations, settle down and develop yourself, always be ready to job-hop</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Become a competition master, take exams (delay employment pressure), or emigrate (escape China's internal competition)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Self-study in college, use the internet to learn the latest knowledge and technologies</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Better understand society's needs, learn with specific goals</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Be yourself, strive to find employment easily even without connections</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I hope everyone can achieve the transformation shown in the image below—from unemployment to landing a decent job.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/06/18/jU3ywtvSpHudihP.webp" alt="Get a decent job"></p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://simone.computer/">Simone computer</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/02/29/ulTjiD8gyawpHzG.webp" alt="Simone computer"></p>
<p>Simone's personal website—a site with retro styling. It makes you feel the nostalgic atmosphere of the early personal computer era, showcasing the charming appeal of classic computer interfaces.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.secaibi.com/howbigisspace/">How High Is the Sky</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/02/29/5S8wTjfeYCE19pt.webp" alt="How High Is the Sky"></p>
<p>A very exquisite interactive webpage introducing the solar system. We just need to scroll the mouse to step from Earth toward the sky, heading to the Moon, Mars, easily traveling through the solar system. It also answers questions along the way—super educational.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://stars.chromeexperiments.com/">100,000 Stars</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cdn.sa.net/2024/02/29/Kp9XZuvGzILa4Wt.webp" alt="100,000 Stars"></p>
<p>An interactive 3D visualization of the stellar neighborhood. Narration in English.</p>
<h2 id="note"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#note"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Note</h2>
<p>Link sharing section completed on February 29, 2024; the rest was completed on July 10, 2023.</p>
<p>Time flies so fast—it's almost been one year since my college graduation.</p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today I Learned #15]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/02/weekly-issue-15</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/02/weekly-issue-15"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's the last semester of university, and my student life might be ending. I really want to take a trip across the country, see the beautiful mountains and rivers of the motherland, then throw myself into work.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/r3W1kNCeThsbnVO.webp" alt="My Yubikey is dead."></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/O8wQng4uZeqaTGA.webp" alt="Yubikey second-hand purchase"></p>
<p>At the end of September last year, Cloudflare and Yubikey partnered to launch a promotional package with a minimum of $10 for a Yubikey 5. At that time, I applied and received Cloudflare's promo code. Since I didn't have time to order from overseas, I carelessly deleted the email containing the Cloudflare promo code.</p>
<p>In December last year, I heard from others that Cloudflare's promo codes would expire at year's end, but my email only keeps deleted messages for 30 days. The email with the Cloudflare promo code was deleted in early October and was already unrecoverable. So I placed an order on the second-hand platform and purchased a Yubikey.</p>
<p>I used this physical key for about 2 months before I broke it in mid-February. I don't have the habit of removing the Yubikey—it stayed plugged into my computer. My laptop sleeve is only big enough for the laptop, leaving the Yubikey sticking out. When I put the physical key along with the sleeve into my backpack, the next time I opened the bag, I found the Yubikey had been snapped.</p>
<p>Currently, I've only experienced adding the Yubikey to my Google, GitHub, and Cloudflare accounts as a physical key for two-factor authentication. This small key has many more functions. When I encounter such deals again in the future, I'll buy a couple more to play with.</p>
<h2 id="topic-today-i-learned"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-today-i-learned"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Today I Learned</h2>
<p><strong>The fastest way to learn is to make your learning process public</strong>. Swyx, the advocate of Learn In Public, mentioned this view in his blog post <a href="https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-public">Learn In Public</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/21/REVGWYQC8Pebd7x.webp" alt="Today I Learned"></p>
<p>I first encountered this view in a domestic blogger's post—I can't remember exactly where. Later, I searched and found the original author's article mentioned above, Learn In Public.</p>
<p>Thinking about your learning notes being published online, you'll definitely take them more seriously because you want to leave a good impression on others. The act of publishing notes indirectly promotes deep learning of a certain field of knowledge.</p>
<p>I once starred a GitHub repository called <a href="https://github.com/jbranchaud/til">til</a>, but didn't look into it at the time. The repository author Josh Branchaud <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22908044">posted</a> this repository on HackerNews. This post inspired Simon Willison, co-creator of the Django framework, so he also created a personal repository to record his learning notes and converted the repository into a <a href="https://til.simonwillison.net/">website</a>. Tonight (February 21, 2023), while organizing my old personal links, I visited Washington Post journalist Kevin Schaul's personal blog. I found that his blog theme is the same as mine—both using the hugo-ivy theme. The "Today I Learned" column caught my attention. This column records the blogger's past learning notes, and he created this column influenced by Simon Willison.</p>
<p>So I also created this column on my personal blog to record my learning notes, make the learning process public, and hopefully achieve the best learning results.</p>
<p>This chain-like propagation of values made me fully appreciate the charm of personal blogs. I hope my sharing can inspire more people to make their learning process public on the internet.</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/RTFM">RTFM</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/08/7DM5jv4AFkgoieW.webp" alt="RTFM"></p>
<p>RTFM is an acronym for "Read The Fucking Manual." Programming often requires consulting official documentation, but official documentation can be long and tedious. When you ask someone a question, if the answer happens to be in the official documentation, the responder can use RTFM to tell you to read the documentation properly to improve yourself. Of course, it's more polite if you also include the specific location in the official documentation.</p>
<p>Note: The emergence of ChatGPT and New Bing has somewhat eased the pain of RTFM (Read The F*cking Manual).</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/TyKB9oYWciznxlE.webp" alt="ChatGPT and RTFM"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://skribbl.io/">skribbl.io</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/ZH3qPieK1Ewgu82.webp" alt="skribbl"></p>
<p>This website is a free online multiplayer drawing and guessing game, inspired by the original drawing game Pictionary. Each round, one player must draw a word they've chosen while other players try to guess it for points! At the end of the game, the person with the highest score is crowned the winner! You can play with friends or join a random game.</p>
<p>On the afternoon of February 27th, I played with foreigners for half an hour—quite fun.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="http://www.milliondollarhomepage.com/">The Million Dollar Homepage</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/3RX2agtd681OUnf.webp" alt="The Million Dollar Homepage"></p>
<p>This website was created in 2005 by British university student Alex Tew to raise money for his college tuition. The homepage consists of one million pixels, with each pixel selling for $1. Buyers could place their own images and links on these pixels. The website made $1 million in just five months and became a miracle in internet history. However, many links on this website are now dead.</p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.webdesignmuseum.org/">Web Design Museum</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/31/oKhaUFROtygi7YI.webp" alt="Web Design Museum"></p>
<p>The Web Design Museum presents past trends of web design that dominated the internet from 1991 to 2006.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://start.dji.com/">start.dji.com</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/08/T3auDXyUYvsHFmS.webp" alt="start.dji.com"></p>
<p>A webpage by DJI that lets you simulate drone operation online. DJI is an advanced Chinese company, especially in the drone field. After I make money from work, I plan to buy a drone to play with.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://www.conventionalcommits.org/en/v1.0.0/">Conventional Commits</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/10/CE9UXfqFs8au3Zy.webp" alt="Conventional Commits"></p>
<p>When the <code>git commit</code> command commits code from the staging area to the local repository, the <code>-m</code> parameter is used to add commit messages. This website can help standardize your commit messages. The About page has a bunch of related tools like VS Code plugins and command-line tools.</p>
<p>Note: AI tools that automatically write commit messages for you have recently appeared—search GitHub for details (AI writes corresponding commit messages based on git repository changes). It's not hard to see that in the near future, ChatGPT+ will integrate with various industries to benefit humanity!</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://phind.com/">phind</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/tzP1cQfJuwLmIej.webp" alt="phind"></p>
<p>An AI search engine designed for developers.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://siteexplainer.vercel.app/">SiteExplainer</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/X2NYEHuzg38rDtC.webp" alt="SiteExplainer"></p>
<p>This website is a tool that uses advanced AI and machine learning to analyze a website's content and provide a summary of key points. It simplifies the language used on landing pages and removes corporate jargon to help visitors better understand website content.</p>
<p>I've only used this tool once—when New Bing's quota was used up, since New Bing allows only 60 conversations per day. For me, New Bing is essentially a summarization tool. On my sticky notes, I keep two prompts ready. When I encounter a long article or a website with unclear functionality, I send the link to New Bing followed by "What does this article say?" (for article links) or "What is this website for?" (for website links), letting New Bing summarize for me.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/28/wveExFpguVJCnl2.webp" alt="sticker"></p>
<p>Recently, I've seen developers create browser plugins for Bilibili video summarization, and last year I saw foreign developers make a YouTube video summarization plugin. Both require OpenAI's API. Both video summaries use ChatGPT + automatically generated video subtitles, letting ChatGPT summarize for you.</p>
<p>I haven't incorporated them into my workflow because I prefer watching videos I'm interested in directly, and I'm also afraid of missing exciting moments in videos.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>Why would anyone care about my life/hobbies/stories?</li>
</ol>
<p>Because we're lonely, we need more friends or sympathetic audiences—those who will listen to our stories and share their own or tell us: they were moved by our stories. We like reading others' stories because they help us affirm our own stories—we're not alone.</p>
<p>-- <a href="https://links.net/dox/tech/whyweb.html">why the web?</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/31/eFUrPJgxvSuZjwE.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Blogger's Code of Conduct</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Take responsibility not only for your own words but also for comments on your blog.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>State your tolerance level for abusive comments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Consider eliminating anonymous comments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don't feed the trolls via RSS.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Talk offline, speak directly, or find an intermediary who can do so.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you know someone who is behaving badly, tell them how they can improve.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don't say anything online that you wouldn't say in person.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>-- <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Blogger&#x27;s_Code_of_Conduct">Blogger's Code of Conduct</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/31/WjAHTFg5ot6a87v.webp" alt="Blogger&#x27;s Code of Conduct"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Businesses vote with their feet (on the domain issue)—they want international or at least nationally neutral domain names. The same freedom should apply to individuals; all individuals should own their own domain names.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="https://nic.eu.org/">Paul Mockapetris, creator of DNS</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/02/02/OJKxXluiVS76NQL.webp" alt="Quote three"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Personal attacks don't elevate yourself or lower others.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- Bilibili user</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>99.5% of actors in China are like me—99.5% of actors are exactly the same as me. At most, only 0.5% of actors are comfortable.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- Actor Zhang Songwen</p>
<p>After listening to interviews with Zhang Songwen, who plays Gao Qiqiang in "The Wild Bunch," I felt deeply moved. Jackson Yee, who's my age, is already worth hundreds of millions, but his acting skills are limited; while truly talented actors are being squeezed dry.</p>
<p>Opportunity is important. If Zhang Songwen hadn't been discovered by director Xu Jizhou to play Gao Qiqiang, he would still be one of countless anonymous actors. But at the same time, it reveals the distorted state of the film industry. To attract more audiences, directors hire traffic celebrities to make their fans pay for tickets. Is this really beneficial for Chinese cinema? If the hired traffic celebrities have acting skills, definitely yes; but if their acting is subpar, definitely not. What Chinese cinema needs is good works and talented actors.</p>
<p>It's time to clean up the film industry—don't let it be captured too deeply by capital!</p>
<h2 id="documentary"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#documentary"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Documentary</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AxD4mqFtySQ">overshare: the links.net story</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/31/NtTUeYqIx4AMJ3b.webp" alt="overshare: the links.net story"></p>
<p>A documentary released by Justin Hall, called "the founding father of personal blogging" by The New York Times in 2004. This documentary shows the impact of his internet sharing on him. Quote one in this newsletter is from an article on his website—links.net.</p>
<h2 id="weekly-blog-post-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#weekly-blog-post-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Weekly Blog Post Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><a href="https://buttondown.email/hillelwayne/archive/maybe-people-do-care-about-performance-and/">Maybe people do care about performance and reliability</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://erich-friedman.github.io/packing/squinsqu/">Squares in Squares</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32801359">Shortest URLs on the Internet</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://infiniteundo.com/post/25326999628/falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-time">Falsehoods programmers believe about time</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://zachholman.com/talk/utc-is-enough-for-everyone-right">UTC is enough for everyone ...right?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://blog.humphd.org/cheatgpt/">CheatGPT</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://grifel.dev/decentralization/">Self hosting in 2023</a></p>
</li>
</ol>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the Internet Have Memory? #14]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-14</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-14"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The performance by Huang Qishan and Curley G on the Spring Festival Gala stage perfectly portrayed the deep bond between mother and daughter.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/RUlQhg1AFNP9yLv.webp" alt="Alashankou Border Defense Company&#x27;s National Gate Observatory on New Year&#x27;s Eve in Xinjiang"></p>
<p>Image source: People's Daily Bilibili live broadcast</p>
<p>On New Year's Eve, during this moment of family reunion, border soldiers guard China's western gateway in the cold wind. Salute!</p>
<p>Attached: <a href="https://maps.baidu.com/search/%E9%98%BF%E6%8B%89%E5%B1%B1%E5%8F%A3%E5%B8%82/@12296363.029602338,3946343.1349892803,5.16z?querytype=s&#x26;da_src=shareurl&#x26;wd=%E9%98%BF%E6%8B%89%E5%B1%B1%E5%8F%A3%E5%B8%82&#x26;c=1&#x26;src=0&#x26;pn=0&#x26;sug=0&#x26;l=5&#x26;b=(734123.3037004266,3831962.189197766;12265633.236013407,9603723.15011067)&#x26;from=webmap&#x26;biz_forward=%7B%22scaler%22:1,%22styles%22:%22pl%22%7D&#x26;device_ratio=1">Location of Alashankou in Xinjiang, China</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/qJBXkKdEgYmHrUx.webp" alt="Baidu Map Alashankou, Xinjiang"></p>
<h2 id="topic-does-the-internet-have-memory"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-does-the-internet-have-memory"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Does the Internet Have Memory?</h2>
<p>The internet is the greatest invention of our era, driving social development and progress and affecting people's lives. But does it really have memory? Of course, this is a dialectical topic. In this discussion, I'll explore from the perspective of internet memory dissipating.</p>
<p>Brewster Kahle, founder of the Internet Archive, mentioned in his blog post<sup><a href="#user-content-fn-1" id="user-content-fnref-1" data-footnote-ref aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup> that web pages have an average lifespan of only about 100 days before being changed or disappearing.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/27/Uw7ps89WRfVPkbl.webp" alt="Brewster Kahle&#x27;s blog post"></p>
<p>Whenever clicking on links first published on the internet years ago, websites that still work are rarely maintained by individuals—most are by businesses or companies. Personal sites are the most fragile part of the internet. Those who persevere with personal sites are few; many webmasters take their sites offline for various reasons.</p>
<p>Sites that go offline without being crawled by the Internet Archive will completely disappear from the internet. At most, only the webmaster has a vague memory that they once built a website, but their memory of what the site looked like will gradually fade with time until extinction. Therefore, the memory nature of the internet isn't absolute—having been here doesn't mean you left traces in this world. Memory requires traces; without them, talking about memory becomes somewhat metaphysical.</p>
<p>Although the Internet Archive preserves traces of personal sites' existence to some extent, this preservation still has issues—it cannot fully reproduce a site's original appearance; there will always be subtle differences from the original. These differences mainly come from embedded elements in web pages, such as embedded videos and PDFs. But overall, the Internet Archive has done remarkably well.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/27/xcd2JnNkYaMo8ZO.webp" alt="Internet Archive"></p>
<p>Therefore, for personal sites, regularly submitting your website to the Internet Archive is particularly necessary—this is how you leave more traces on the internet.</p>
<p>There are also methods to save entire sites—including external elements. For specific methods, see this <a href="https://webapps.stackexchange.com/questions/115369/how-to-archive-the-whole-website">post</a>.</p>
<p>Below is the progress after I sought help in the ArchiveBot channel, showing the archival process of my website by the ArchiveBot administrator. It's clear that archiving an entire site includes archiving the external sites it links to. This is the most effective way to archive a whole site—you must archive the external sites your site references to truly preserve the whole site's memory.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/27/fIhStWTACFq4nHP.webp" alt="ArchiveBot archiving personal site"></p>
<p>Of course, this type of archival is costly, so ArchiveBot administrators add ignore rules to the archival program to save costs.</p>
<p>Last year, Baidu search engine discontinued its snapshot feature. Baidu claimed, "As technology matures and website stability can be guaranteed, the snapshot feature is no longer needed." But is that really the case? I personally disagree with Baidu's approach. The snapshot feature still has value for users wanting to see what taken-down websites looked like. Hastily removing the snapshot feature further dissipates internet memory.</p>
<p>The internet needs not just fast-food, disposable culture—it needs an archival service to preserve its memory. Undoubtedly, the Internet Archive is ahead of its time in this regard. While there may be controversial content archived there too, this doesn't diminish its value and significance.</p>
<p>You can say the internet has memory, but don't forget its fragility. Remember to use the Internet Archive more to preserve your traces on the internet!</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li>The shortest path doesn't equal the fastest path.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/UNqoZhCV9GmH1eA.gif" alt="The shortest path doesn&#x27;t equal the fastest path."></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>English prepositions GIF demonstration.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/sbAFjlmHqXU4ZRY.gif" alt="English prepositions GIF demonstration"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>On January 26, 2023, NBA Warriors home game against the Grizzlies, Curry was ejected for throwing his mouthguard.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="/gif/2023-01-26-curry-throws-his-mouthpiece.gif" alt="Curry ejected for throwing his mouthguard"></p>
<p>The interesting part is that Curry was applauding Poole's 3-point attempt just a second before, but when he saw the shot missed, Curry angrily threw his mouthguard. The contrast is hilarious—truly deserving of his nickname "Baby Face."</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Cloudflare uses lava lamp wall to help encrypt the internet.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/27/Nv8RAbzP7nQYmlX.webp" alt="Cloudflare lava lamp wall helps encrypt the internet."></p>
<p>A 2017 tech news story. Cloudflare is a well-known tech company providing services like CDN acceleration and DDoS protection. Due to computers' shortcomings in randomness, Cloudflare uses photos of 100 lava lamps converted into random data for SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption.</p>
<p>Appendix 1: <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/ssl/lava-lamp-encryption/">Cloudflare blog</a></p>
<p>Appendix 2: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eGaZpb3rP_I">YouTube video link</a></p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://info.cern.ch/">Home of the first website</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/FOu4tKMCqvrXo1H.webp" alt="Screenshot of the recreated page of the first website (Image: CERN)"></p>
<p>When learning computer networks, we only learn that the inventor of the World Wide Web is Sir Tim Berners-Lee from the UK. But there's actually a story about the internet's origins worth exploring.</p>
<p>Sir Tim Berners-Lee launched the first website on December 20, 1990. The site was hosted on a NeXT computer at CERN (European Organization for Nuclear Research) and was only accessible within CERN's internal network. It was dedicated to providing information about the World Wide Web project. It went public on August 6, 1991<sup><a href="#user-content-fn-2" id="user-content-fnref-2" data-footnote-ref aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Later, for various reasons<sup><a href="#user-content-fn-3" id="user-content-fnref-3" data-footnote-ref aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup>, the first website was lost. In 2013, CERN restored the site<sup><a href="#user-content-fn-4" id="user-content-fnref-4" data-footnote-ref aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup>. But if you access it with a modern browser, you might not see the image shown above. That's because the image is a screenshot of the first website accessed through the Line Mode Browser (the world's second web browser).</p>
<p>CERN's restored first website homepage also provides an option to browse using the Line Mode Browser, but currently (as of January 26, 2023), clicking on it with modern browsers gives a 503 Service Unavailable error<sup><a href="#user-content-fn-5" id="user-content-fnref-5" data-footnote-ref aria-describedby="footnote-label">5</a></sup>. For more details, see the <a href="https://line-mode.cern.ch/">Line Mode Browser 2013</a> page.</p>
<p>Appendix 1: Sir Tim Berners-Lee was honored as the "Inventor of the World Wide Web" at the London Olympics, using an old NeXT computer at the opening ceremony. "This Is For Everyone" fully demonstrated his open-source spirit. <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Nk4y1k7R1/">Bilibili video link</a></p>
<p>Appendix 2: In 2014, computer enthusiast Suhayl Khan demonstrated how to access the Line Mode Browser using 1960s technology—commemorating the 25th anniversary of the World Wide Web. <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1RW411w783/">Bilibili video link</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/qatRHhN9sSzTPGe.webp" alt="This is for everyone."></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://code.golf/">Code Golf</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/23/QjGV6FXExKZAedD.webp" alt="Code Golf"></p>
<p>A programming game website—solve problems with the fewest bytes/characters to get higher rankings. <a href="https://github.com/code-golf/code-golf">Project open source</a></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://computerhistory.org/">Computer History Museum</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/26/Fmoq8V5E67rgAJv.webp" alt="Computer History Museum"></p>
<p>This website is dedicated to decoding computer technology and computer history-related content.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://how-i-experience-web-today.com/detail.html#">how-i-experience-web-today</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/26/T7GyCdrqW96Ze5O.webp" alt="how-i-experience-web-today"></p>
<p>This website demonstrates the current state of contemporary internet experience. Cookie privacy statements, website notifications, newsletter subscriptions, requests to pay when ad blockers are detected, pop-ups... Of course, this is just the situation abroad.</p>
<p>In China, the internet experience generally happens on mobile. But mobile is the same—splash ads, app pop-ups... Although there are ways to block them, these profit-driven nuisances seriously impact user experience.</p>
<p>Recently, I saw a post on HackerNews "thanking HackerNews for being ad-free, etc." A comment there made me laugh.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/25/M1rIkOblGxysCqv.webp" alt="HackerNews user comment"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Ironically, so many professionals come to HackerNews to breathe fresh air, after which they go back to building the user experience they originally fled from. -- <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34505635">HackerNews user comment</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Commenters replying to this note that developers don't have a say in user experience. Indeed, those who truly define user experience are bosses and capital. Programmers work for bosses to feed their families. Facing things they dislike that are added for users, they can only add them according to the boss's wishes.</p>
<p>I hope in the future, there's technology that can free user experience from capital's grip and return the internet to purity!</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://reddit1.nbastreamlinks.net/">nbastreamlinks</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/26/srzNEF2uip7bxIo.webp" alt="nbastreamlinks"></p>
<ol start="6">
<li><a href="https://nbastreams.app/">nbastreams</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/26/mB5GAIjMRJS1ChU.webp" alt="nbastreams"></p>
<p>These two foreign websites allow you to watch NBA live streams for free. Achieve NBA viewing freedom.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>For me, writing your own styles is like writing test code: a little slow at first, but the early effort pays off. In the long run, you'll save a lot of time, energy, and frustration.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2022/05/you-dont-need-ui-framework">You Don't Need A UI Framework</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/23/8YnOj1xscTptVoz.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>What reader is smarter and more suitable for the masses, and will become a replacement for Google Reader? My team and I answered: algorithm-based personalized recommendations.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="http://m.techweb.com.cn/article/2013-03-14/1283033.shtml">Applauding Page's Courage to Shut Down Google Reader!</a></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Basically, if we want to return the internet to users' hands, we need to decouple "services" from "storage." Companies should not be allowed to hold user data hostage.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32687972">HackerNews reader</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/21/CLP4Iq1r9bREMVa.webp" alt="Quote three"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>But I appreciate Jason Werner's (former GitHub CTO) view more. He believes AI will replace developers' jobs the same way C and JavaScript "replaced" early developers writing assembly code. They didn't really replace those developers—they just introduced another layer of abstraction and automation, fundamentally changing how they program and interact with computers.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="https://bytes.dev/archives/143">Bytes</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/23/uGIBHpXl9ie4kY1.webp" alt="Quote four"></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Playing games is a voluntary attempt to overcome unnecessary obstacles.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2022/12/you-dont-need-html/">YOU DON'T NEED HTML!</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/23/jZE2RIt4N7HYCno.webp" alt="Quote five"></p>
<ol start="6">
<li>Nobody truly owns a domain name, just as nobody truly owns a piece of land. Before it belongs to anyone, it has been traded with many parties; in this case, the parties can sell it and buy new land. Everything is borrowed.</li>
</ol>
<p>-- <a href="https://thoughtstreams.io/higgins/permalinking-vs-transience/">Permalinking vs Transience.</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/24/MxVIblHhuwYDy4z.webp" alt="Quote six"></p>
<section data-footnotes class="footnotes"><h2 class="sr-only" id="footnote-label"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#footnote-label"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Footnotes</h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1">
<p><a href="https://brewster.kahle.org/2015/08/11/locking-the-web-open-a-call-for-a-distributed-web-2/">Brewster Kahle's blog post</a> <a href="#user-content-fnref-1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2">
<p><a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Tim_Berners-Lee">Tim_Berners-Lee</a> <a href="#user-content-fnref-2" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3">
<p>Although I've reviewed many online resources, none explain in detail. Website going offline is likely due to the NeXT computer's limited lifespan, etc. In that era, hosting a website required having your own server and keeping it running 24/7. Keeping it on 24/7 couldn't last many years for machines of that era—unlike today's cloud servers where hardware updates and iterations happen without user awareness. <a href="#user-content-fnref-3" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4">
<p><a href="https://first-website.web.cern.ch/first-website/">Restoring the first website</a> <a href="#user-content-fnref-4" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-5">
<p>I also tried finding archives in the Internet Archive of when you could use the Line Mode Browser to access the first website in modern browsers, but the archived pages display poorly. <a href="#user-content-fnref-5" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 5" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Bad Habit of Hoarding Information #13]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-13</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-13"/>
        <updated>2023-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The song title is "You Have Me," not "Fearless You." The original singer is Zhou Shen. Curley G's performance at the 2023 CCTV Online Spring Gala was stunning.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/19/E7F2urLpvn6WK9j.webp" alt="Image a World Without Free Knowledge"></p>
<p>Translation:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Imagine a world without free knowledge.</p>
<p>For over a decade, we have spent millions of hours building the greatest encyclopedia in human history. Now the US Congress is considering legislation that could ultimately harm the free and open Internet. To raise public awareness, we are shutting down Wikipedia.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On January 18, 2012, Wikipedia shut down the English Wikipedia for 24 hours to protest against two bills being considered by the US Congress (SOPA and PIPA). The conflict between intellectual property and knowledge sharing continues to clash in today's human society. How to find a balance between the two is worth our consideration.</p>
<p>Note:</p>
<ul>
<li>SOPA: Stop Online Piracy Act</li>
<li>PIPA: Protect IP Act</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:SOPA_initiative/Learn_more">Image source</a></p>
<h2 id="topic-the-bad-habit-of-hoarding-information"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-the-bad-habit-of-hoarding-information"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: The Bad Habit of Hoarding Information</h2>
<p>A few days ago, I came across an article titled <a href="https://andreisurugiu.com/blog/bad-habit/">My bad habit of hoarding information</a>. The author says he's a tech geek who likes to collect all kinds of interesting information from the internet. In the article, he points out that when the number of links to process in a week grows to over 80, processing all these links is very time-consuming—the workload is enormous.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/xELWwcToDpkbePy.webp" alt="My bad habit of hoarding information image one"></p>
<p>The author also reflects on why he developed this information-collecting habit. It might be due to FOMO (Fear Of Missing Out)—afraid of missing interesting links—or perhaps some form of perfectionism. But regardless of the reason, the end result is spending a lot of energy collecting endless links without time to go back and organize them.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/aGX6jBYdVKgwmWq.webp" alt="FOMO"></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q5zv9_ZgYoQ">Image source</a></p>
<p>Actually, I've experienced this too and have only recently started to adjust. Before writing the blog post <a href="https://blog.gujiakai.top/2023/01/read-later-equals-to-not-read.html">"Read Later = Never Read"</a>, I also suffered from FOMO, afraid of missing various exciting news or trending topics on the internet. But after collecting interesting information, I would put them in cold storage, leaving them to gather dust in my bookmarks.</p>
<p>As my bookmarks accumulated more and more, I could no longer tolerate this inefficient, futile collecting. Although there are indeed gems in my bookmarks, most are certainly garbage that doesn't help my personal improvement. So I started clearing bookmarks across all platforms.</p>
<p>I still collect links, but my current collecting has an additional layer of filtering compared to before—that filter is my reading. Only those links that I find valuable and have actually read will I add to my bookmarks for sharing or revisiting later. But these links that make it to my bookmarks are few. Most links I encounter in a day, I close after reading and never let them pollute my bookmarks.</p>
<p>In recent years, various productivity software has emerged endlessly, but have these productivity tools really improved my efficiency? I always reflect on this question. At first, I focused on writing in Typora. Later, hearing that Notion and Obsidian were powerful, I tried writing diaries or notes in these apps, but the results were unsatisfactory. When Notion's new AI feature and Obsidian's new canvas feature launched, they stirred up excitement in the productivity software tinkering community, but I ultimately chose to leave and continue using Typora for writing.</p>
<p>Actually, tinkering with productivity software and hoarding information are the same principle. The essence is that you're trying to use your limited energy to gather unlimited knowledge or engage in endless tinkering to obtain continuous dopamine hits. In this process, you do gain pleasure, but you also scatter your energy, thus reducing your quality of life.</p>
<p>In the <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34272834">HackerNews discussion</a> about the <a href="https://andreisurugiu.com/blog/bad-habit/">My bad habit of hoarding information</a> article, I saw some comments like this. The commenter below is a cautionary tale—he has 24,000+ links stored in the OneTab browser extension. If he doesn't clear them, I estimate he'll have difficulty consuming so many links in his lifetime.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/7yOU8I2wqclXbnT.webp" alt="HackerNews discussion image one"></p>
<p>One commenter shared experience drawn from recent reading: focus on knowledge output rather than knowledge consumption.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/ZvlDN7FImTPnes2.webp" alt="HackerNews discussion image two"></p>
<p>I quite agree with this view. Writing newsletters is a form of knowledge output. Even if the newsletter goes unnoticed, that's not something I should worry about. My focus is on completing and proofreading the newsletter and publishing it, sharing my thoughts with the world—being a knowledge producer in addition to being a consumer.</p>
<p>"My life has limits, but knowledge has none." To pursue the limitless with the limited will exhaust you and leave you empty-handed. Don't use your finite life chasing infinite knowledge.</p>
<p>If there really were a technology that could permanently store all the links you visit daily and provide search functionality, hoarding information wouldn't be a concern—you'd just need to tag well when hoarding, and when writing later, you could search for whatever knowledge you need. Undeniably, reading an article before citing it leaves the deepest impression, but unfortunately, no such service exists.</p>
<p>Therefore, abandoning the bad habit of hoarding information early and focusing more on knowledge output alongside knowledge input is the royal road to escaping the information explosion era.</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li>On the internet, nobody knows you're a dog. This cartoon was published in The New Yorker magazine in 1993, fully embodying the anonymity of the internet. In the 21st century today, there's virtually no privacy left—unless you go offline, you're completely exposed. When you use an app and thoughtlessly check "I have read and agree to the relevant terms of service," you've already sold yourself to tech giants.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/19/ymAR4EFT5D1IwOe.webp" alt="On the internet, nobody knows you&#x27;re a dog."></p>
<p><a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/On_the_Internet,_nobody_knows_you%27re_a_dog">Image source</a></p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://explainshell.com">explainshell</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/19/xAUDEijNsZKBT5t.webp" alt="explainshell demo"></p>
<p>This website can help you learn about shell commands. The image above shows the tar command and the meaning of its parameters.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://crontab.guru">crontab guru</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/19/AgLnW9xuOGEzYHh.webp" alt="crontab guru"></p>
<p>To implement scheduled tasks on Linux, you need cron expressions. This website can help you learn cron expressions.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://killedbymicrosoft.info">Killed by Microsoft</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/78MlYnCQ4KJepuf.webp" alt="Killed by Microsoft"></p>
<p>This website lists products and services killed by tech giant Microsoft, including services familiar to us like IE and Atom. <a href="https://github.com/fabianoriccardi/killed-by-microsoft">Project open source</a>.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://metrodb.org">China Metro Information Overview</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/Wy4Uj2zDQh7HeSM.webp" alt="China Metro Information Overview"></p>
<p>This website provides metro information for major Chinese cities. The image above shows Nanjing metro information.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://blog.itakeo.com/blog/?p=915">Like Collecting</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/m2Oj3df4tUR5Wi8.webp" alt="Like Collecting"></p>
<p>If a merchant wants to promote their brand through WeChat like-collecting campaigns, you can use this guide to easily complete the task. Currently, the program supports up to 200 likes and 15 comments with high customization. The program faithfully replicates the WeChat interface and can easily fool like-collecting event organizers. As shown in the image, I used this program to generate a post with 200 likes and 15 comments.</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><a href="https://thispersondoesnotexist.com">this person does not exist</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/u7A8vyIBFoOd5jY.webp" alt="this person does not exist"></p>
<p>The human photos provided by this website are all generated by GAN (Generative Adversarial Network). Every time you press F5 to refresh the page, a different photo appears. The links in the bottom right corner also provide other similar websites. There's an <a href="https://easyai.tech/ai-definition/gan">accessible article</a> explaining what GAN is.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li><a href="https://www.e-dunhuang.com">Digital Dunhuang</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/Vi7MQwPG2uBX456.webp" alt="Digital Dunhuang"></p>
<p>When mentioning Dunhuang, people's first reaction is the Mogao Caves, but there's more than just the Mogao Caves. Dunhuang grottoes include the Mogao Caves, West Thousand Buddha Caves, and other cave complexes. This website can take you on a tour of the Dunhuang grottoes.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li><a href="https://piyao.kepuchina.cn/rumor/rumorlist">Science Rumor Debunking</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/2ZrhiXGw4kVmNj1.webp" alt="Science Rumor Debunking"></p>
<p>A rumor-debunking website launched by the Cyberspace Administration of China, answering people's questions.</p>
<ol start="9">
<li><a href="https://zh-hans.tld-list.com">Top Level Domain List</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/v417mIoNReaVLnO.webp" alt="Top Level Domain List"></p>
<p>This website provides price data from various top-level domain registrars to help you find the most affordable domain registrar. Domain registration is an investment (for reselling at a markup), but currently, short and memorable domain names have long been registered. If you want to build your own personal website like me to share what you want to share, when you reach the step of purchasing a domain, I recommend checking this website.</p>
<ol start="10">
<li><a href="https://hoten.cc/fireworks/play">Fireworks</a> and <a href="https://fireworks.nianbroken.top">Firework Simulator</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/m5yiSVeKlEOhvrg.webp" alt="Fireworks"></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/heZigdjI6JbOsXq.webp" alt="Firework Simulator"></p>
<p>As Spring Festival approaches, some regions in mainland China prohibit fireworks. These websites let you watch fireworks shows in your browser. The Firework Simulator feels more immersive.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>You shouldn't worry about whether your sharing is valuable. If you want to share it, it's already valuable: it reflects who you are and how you see the world. <a href="https://getblogging.org">via</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/Nq2Kl3Ij6o19XVQ.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>His greatest work is the People's Republic of China. <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1GW411o7dM">Into Mao Zedong documentary</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/jWRJpvI3HT2Min6.webp" alt="Quote two"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Richard Stallman, founder of the Free Software Foundation, said: "Solving some difficult problem out of interest, regardless of whether it's useful or not—that's hacking."</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/diwcSvRtEaYljBG.webp" alt="Quote three"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Notes can be scattered—just record what you see or think. It's knowledge input. Blogs are often systematic organization, thinking, and summarizing—knowledge output.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/hyJkWcH7Xz5qAiC.webp" alt="Quote four"></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Freedom is being free to say that 2+2=4.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/20/uUtVOCv2JynKXZ5.webp" alt="Quote five"></p>
<h2 id="happy-spring-festival-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#happy-spring-festival-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Happy Spring Festival! 🎆🎇🧧</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break Through During Graduation Season? #12]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-12</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-12"/>
        <updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This song is Nicholas Teo's performance on Hunan TV's show "Time Music Concert" last year. The video version can be found at &#x3C;a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1dd4y1s7Sc/" target="_blank">Bilibili link&#x3C;/a>.</p>
<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/cxfkZmjUBWdhG7O.webp" alt="Blue Marble"></p>
<p>On December 7, 1972, astronauts on Apollo 17 took this photo of Earth on their way to the Moon. Today known as the "Blue Marble," this photo has become one of the most iconic images of our home. <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/content/blue-marble-image-of-the-earth-from-apollo-17">Image source</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/o4XRcxlpAYm2HeT.webp" alt="Photo taken by Shenzhou-14 astronauts in orbit"></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/c4bXmZ79xoSetMn.webp" alt="Yellow River estuary"></p>
<p>The Shenzhou-14 manned spaceflight mission (June 5 to December 4, 2022) was the first manned spaceflight mission in China's space station construction phase, carrying three astronauts: Chen Dong, Cai Xuzhe, and Liu Yang. Image two was taken by astronaut Chen Dong during the mission. Based on my comparison with maps, image two shows China's Yellow River estuary. <a href="http://www.cmse.gov.cn/dmt/tj/202212/t20221217_51935.html">Image two source</a> <a href="https://maps.baidu.com/@13147931.71249071,4454683.06030799,9.13z/maptype%3DB_EARTH_MAP">Image three source</a></p>
<p>Apollo 17 was humanity's last trip to the Moon. Humans haven't returned to the Moon in the past 50 years because lunar missions are extremely expensive, and the Moon is basically a barren desert—it's not worth spending a fortune to send astronauts for a stroll. However, China hasn't landed on the Moon yet, and the technology and experience for lunar landing are essential. Currently, China's manned space program's three-step strategy has reached the third step. I believe that someday in the future, China will also achieve its lunar landing dream.</p>
<h2 id="topic-how-to-break-through-during-graduation-season"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-how-to-break-through-during-graduation-season"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: How to Break Through During Graduation Season?</h2>
<p>Teacher Ruan Yifeng discussed in last year's newsletter article—&#x3C;a href="https://www.ruanyifeng.com/blog/2022/12/weekly-issue-235.html#comment-text" target="_blank">Youth Unemployment Rate and Choosing Entrepreneurship&#x3C;/a>—why it's difficult for fresh graduates to start businesses and how to cope with the severe employment situation. Recommended reading.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/aIyWP4pF7fV3Kun.webp" alt="Youth unemployment rate and choosing entrepreneurship highlights"></p>
<p>Today is January 12, 2023, with only 5 months left until the Class of 2023 graduates. If the postgraduate exam doesn't work out, what should we do? In the remaining 5 months, how can computer science students make efforts? I'll share my personal views on these two questions.</p>
<p>Of course, if you're very confident about your postgraduate entrance exam, you can start preparing for the interview in advance without worrying too much about future employment—passing the exam will delay your job search, giving you another 2-3 years as a student. If you're not confident about the initial exam, you can either start preparing for the interview or wait until the scores come out to make interview plans.</p>
<p>For those not confident about the initial exam and not busy with interview preparation, here are my suggestions for entering the workforce:</p>
<p>First, choose one programming language to study deeply, gradually meeting the requirements of your desired position. That is, learn relevant technologies based on job requirements.</p>
<p>As shown in the image below, describing the requirements for a Go language backend development position. If you're interested in this position, you can follow the description and learn the relevant technologies step by step.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/13/Rdk8iwLGzchN2jE.webp" alt="Go language backend development requirements"></p>
<p>Second, focus on developing self-learning abilities. Pay attention to computer fundamentals and don't over-rely on technical frameworks.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/13/1q3K5fZjkFLaDHc.webp" alt="Today&#x27;s developers"></p>
<p>Undoubtedly, technical frameworks are your stepping stone for future employment—they're indeed important, but computer fundamentals are more important. For example, before learning Vue, a frontend framework, you must solidify your knowledge of HTML, CSS, JS, Node.js, etc. Frameworks provide you with a template; you don't need to reinvent the wheel from scratch. Just consult the official documentation, combine it with your needs to write code, and you can achieve your desired functionality. But the unchanging foundation behind these frameworks is always computer fundamentals.</p>
<p>Self-learning ability is also crucial—it determines how far you can go. Technology iterates too fast. To avoid being eliminated by the times, you must learn to self-study. Initially, you might choose to watch videos on Bilibili to learn a programming language, but when you learn another language, can you self-study just from the official documentation? This is a test of your self-learning ability. If you can't, you'll only learn some commonly used knowledge, and when asked to explain deeper content, you'll be at a loss.</p>
<p>Self-learning ability isn't innate or achieved overnight. It requires deliberate practice—push yourself to self-study, and gradually you'll appreciate the charm of self-learning.</p>
<p>Third, find the value, meaning, and original intention of learning. Don't let learning become low-level, inefficient training. <a href="https://weibo.com/2365961811/MijbVmz6O">via</a> Cultivate your own personality and interests.</p>
<p>High school study might just be to cope with the college entrance exam; university study might just be for graduation and postgraduate exams. But think carefully—how much does this actually improve you? Never let your student life wear down your edges.</p>
<p>There's an interesting phenomenon on university campuses: in freshman year, there are still several students who actively speak up in class. But as time goes on, few students actively participate. After a teacher poses a question, there's dead silence. In my view, this deserves attention. If you have ideas, you should boldly raise your hand to share and demonstrate your ideas and confidence.</p>
<p>The value, meaning, and original intention of learning is to improve yourself—both in ability and other aspects. You might initially know nothing about computer science, but as you learn, I hope you'll fall in love with your major and its field. Remember to follow tech news regularly and keep a pulse on the industry.</p>
<p>Interest is the best teacher. Only when you're passionate enough can you learn faster and more. In my view, the best way to combat involution is to cultivate your own interests and personality.</p>
<p>In summary, stay sharp, keep learning, love life, and find your foothold in society early. Keep looking up at the stars, open your eyes to the world—don't limit your vision to just your university or your country. Think globally!</p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li>Vietnamese Year of the Cat.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/41sMXQYEyi6Hp29.webp" alt="2023 is the Year of the Cat in Vietnam"></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/oc4JLFOeq6m9KSA.webp" alt="2023 Spring Festival Gala mascot—Rabbit Yuanyuan"></p>
<p>Like China, Spring Festival is Vietnam's most important traditional holiday. But unlike China, Vietnam's zodiac uses the Cat instead of the Rabbit. There are various explanations for this. One theory suggests that when Chinese culture spread to Vietnam, Vietnamese people misheard "Year of Mao (Rabbit)" as "Year of Mao (Cat)"; another theory maintains that Vietnamese value "ecological balance"—since there's a Rat in the zodiac, the Cat can counter it. &#x3C;a href="https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E7%8C%AB%E5%B9%B4/4943704" target="_blank">via&#x3C;/a></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Web Development Acronyms</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/NVBGYuXcKMor8m1.webp" alt="Fake web development acronyms"></p>
<p>When I first encountered this image, I didn't look carefully and saved it to my bookmarks. When I later had time to review it, I found the image was completely nonsense—it can be seen as a humor image from programmers. The real web development acronyms are shown below.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/sxzMjkZQctoWeY3.webp" alt="Real web development acronyms"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://ossinsight.io/2022/">Trends and Insights from GitHub 2022</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/OPmS3EAInfD5kNH.webp" alt="Developer behavior analysis"></p>
<p>Chinese developers like to star repositories, with WatchEvent at 17.23% and ForkEvent at 2.7%. This probably describes GitHub users like me. In the past year, I starred nearly 3,000 repositories, but I've actually used and understood very few. So a few days ago, I removed all my stars. Using GitHub's API can quickly accomplish clearing all stars.</p>
<p>In my view, Chinese developers need to work harder—transition from Watch, Fork, Star to Pull Request. Contribute more code; change the world with code.</p>
<p>The article mentioned that the top language in the open-source world over the past four years is JavaScript. Below is a joke image about JS that I saw in a group.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/dxFGJqDniAOh5X3.webp" alt="Joke about JS"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trivia about a.m. and p.m.</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/tLbcp1QVYUjhNk2.webp" alt="Trivia about a.m. and p.m."></p>
<p>For an explanation of a.m. and p.m., refer to <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/time/am-and-pm.html">this link</a>.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Two Ways to Browse GitHub Repositories in VSCode Mode</li>
</ol>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Change the domain github.com to github.dev / Press the period (.) key on your keyboard</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Add 1s after github in the domain</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.gapminder.org/dollar-street">Dollar Street</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/jYaAzEq7pOG8PsT.webp" alt="Dollar Street"></p>
<p>This website shows the monthly income levels of families around the world. You can adjust the range yourself—the further left the range, the poorer the family; the further right, the wealthier. It's not hard to see that the gap between rich and poor in the world is still quite large. But for human society to progress, there must be differences. If egalitarianism is adopted, people's laziness will inevitably increase, and the spirit of striving and chasing dreams will be worn down.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="http://music.alang.run">Listen to Music Together</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/9vgWs65JLy4EbAM.webp" alt="Listen to Music Together"></p>
<p>When hanging out with friends, why not create a room on this website and listen to music together? The project is <a href="https://github.com/JumpAlang/Jusic-serve">open source</a> and can be self-deployed.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://www.my80stv.com">My 80's TV!</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/to5hZ2dkLvTUKeP.webp" alt="My 80&#x27;s TV!"></p>
<p>This website was created by Joey Cato from the San Francisco Bay Area in California, USA. It shows us the content broadcast on American TVs in the 1980s. The TV I opened in the image above is playing a music program. Joey Cato likes to create interactive, nostalgic things in his spare time. He believes it's a fun way to exercise his passion for learning. <a href="https://www.joeycato.com">via</a></p>
<p>It's not hard to see that besides 80s TV, there are also 60s, 70s, 90s, and 00s TVs. This webmaster's creative spirit is worth learning from.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://sou-yun.cn/PoetLifeMap.aspx">Tang and Song Dynasty Literature Chronological Map</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/ywlPJgsfrG6LouS.webp" alt="Tang and Song Dynasty Literature Chronological Map"></p>
<p>Su Shi, a poet from China's Northern Song Dynasty, once wrote: "Ask about my life's achievements: Huangzhou, Huizhou, Danzhou." This fully demonstrates his open-minded self-deprecation despite being demoted.</p>
<p>But a question remains: where exactly are Huangzhou, Huizhou, and Danzhou? Through this website, you can clearly see Su Dongpo's footprints throughout his life and the locations of those three states at that time.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/2oCdlOL5GZ4c7kE.webp" alt="Su Shi&#x27;s life footprints"></p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="http://johnburnmurdoch.github.io/projects/goal-lines/all-comps">The top goal-scorers in elite club football since 1980</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/u8tHezgD37kLlIm.webp" alt="The top goal-scorers in elite club football since 1980"></p>
<p>This website records the top scorers in elite clubs since 1980. Data sources include Premier League, La Liga, Serie A, Bundesliga, Ligue 1, and other competitions.</p>
<p>When it comes to football, people's first impression is Messi and Ronaldo. The reason is that these two legends have the highest goal rankings, as clearly shown in the image above.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>I believe that computer science as a field is facing quite a large upheaval, and very few of us are really prepared for it. <a href="https://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2023/1/267976-the-end-of-programming/fulltext">via</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/Em56TvGAQrSp3Ka.webp" alt="Quote one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>I also hate all weather forecasters who tell people rainy days are bad weather. There's no such thing as bad weather, only wrong clothing. So put on a sexy raincoat on rainy days and enjoy life. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/raining/comments/zanvhh/hope_this_is_allowed_here_made_me_think_of_yall">via</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/1y5OBJEK4RFUIhC.webp" alt="Quote two"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<p>The best way to break information silos is sharing—a power everyone has.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In the learning pyramid, note that those belonging to "active learning" are behaviors with "strong output" characteristics. So conversely, it shows that more output leads to better learning. <a href="https://t.me/codedump_notes/237">via</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/12/oBGFVLtynw6I4TY.webp" alt="Quote four image"></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Dating should happen in your 20s. After that time passes, finding a partner is just making do, not about love.</li>
</ol>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello 2023 #11]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-11</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2023/01/weekly-issue-11"/>
        <updated>2023-01-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="cover-image"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cover-image"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Cover Image</h2>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/02/aEuIAXRplML1ib6.webp" alt="Unsplash 2022 Photo of the Year Award"></p>
<p>"This image has an otherworldly quality to it, creating a moment of calm and tranquility in this otherwise chaotic world we live in." — Unsplash 2022 Photo of the Year Award. <a href="https://awards.unsplash.com/2022/#/community-photo">(via)</a></p>
<h2 id="topic-hello-2023"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-hello-2023"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Hello 2023</h2>
&#x3C;iframe src="https://player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=519647638&#x26;bvid=BV1Wg411x7sx&#x26;cid=948309604&#x26;page=1&#x26;autoplay=0"  scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" class="bilibili"> &#x3C;/iframe>
<p>It's been a long time since I wrote a newsletter. I still remember the last time I wrote was in June of last year. In the blink of an eye, 2022 has already left us. Just as shown in the video above, 2022 is no longer in the stream of time.</p>
<p>Whether for the world or for me personally, 2022 was a challenging year.</p>
<p>This year, the pandemic continued to plague the world. Humanity didn't successfully defeat COVID-19; instead, the process of coexisting with it accelerated. This year, many notable figures left us, and with their passing, the cruelty of time was once again displayed before the world. At the end of this year, I successfully joined the Communist Party of China, though I'm well aware that I still have some distance to becoming a qualified party member. This year, for the postgraduate entrance examination at year's end, I gave up programming, hobbies, and more. After the initial exam, knowing that I probably wouldn't succeed in becoming a graduate student on my first attempt, in about half a year I'll likely enter the workforce, learning from experience...</p>
<p>In 2022, <a href="https://about.google/stories/year-in-search/">Google's search keyword was "can I change"</a>; <a href="https://languages.oup.com/word-of-the-year/2022/">Oxford Dictionary's word of the year was "goblin mode"</a>; <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/blackboard/activity-Lvg7KQjIag.html">Bilibili's annual comment was "elegant"</a>...</p>
<p>For me, the keywords of 2022 were the postgraduate exam and graduation. After undergraduate graduation, where should I go? To ease my confusion, I followed the crowd and took the postgraduate exam. At the same time, to prepare for graduation, I was also working on my thesis. My ordinary life was fulfilling yet busy.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/02/KgnlDVQxm6biZA9.webp" alt="Personal annual summary"></p>
<h2 id="interesting"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interesting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Interesting</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://archiveprogram.github.com/">Preserving Open Source Software for Future Generations</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A project from the world's largest code hosting platform, GitHub—the Archive Program. Reportedly, on February 2, 2020, GitHub captured a snapshot of every active open-source repository and stored it in an abandoned coal mine deep in the Arctic mountains of Svalbard, Norway.</p>
&#x3C;iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=711477211&#x26;bvid=BV1rD4y1m78m&#x26;cid=214423471&#x26;page=1&#x26;autoplay=0" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" class="bilibili"> &#x3C;/iframe>
<p>Here's a location map of the Svalbard archipelago, located in northern Europe, close to the North Pole.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/02/O3Q47U8tDaV1IH2.webp" alt="Svalbard location"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MTRelaxation67/comments/z88ihb/what_happens_when_a_desert_gets_rain/">What happens when a desert gets continuous heavy rain?</a></li>
</ol>
&#x3C;iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=222212428&#x26;bvid=BV198411E7e2&#x26;cid=948497301&#x26;page=1&#x26;autoplay=0" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" class="bilibili"> &#x3C;/iframe>
<p>Surprisingly, it causes floods—I didn't expect that. Nature is truly amazing.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/weirddalle/comments/zi14ae/a_developer_finding_a_bug_now_even_more_literal/">AI-Generated Bug Illustration</a></li>
</ol>
<p>The term "Bug" in software refers to small errors or glitches in programs. The origin of this term is fascinating—it comes from a moth found in a relay. 2022 can be called the inaugural year of AI art, with various AI painting programs emerging one after another.</p>
<p>A foreign netizen used Midjourney, an AI painting software, to create an image containing a giant bug.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/02/2GXpwSm9gbKYNkP.webp" alt="A developer found a bug"></p>
&#x3C;center>&#x3C;b>A developer found a bug.&#x3C;/b>&#x3C;/center>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://oldcomputers.net/">Steve's Old Computer Museum</a></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/02/hvIUFY1OsCun3WG.webp" alt="Steve&#x27;s Old Computer Museum homepage"></p>
<p>This website is dedicated to preserving and displaying vintage computer systems. The site maintainer is Steve Stengel from Orange County, Los Angeles, California, USA. Based on various materials on the site, he's a vintage computer enthusiast.</p>
<p>Browsing through the timeline on the left side of the website, it's not hard to see that older vintage computer systems were more expensive, while more modern vintage systems were cheaper.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://mail.totime.cn/">Cloud Time Post Office</a></li>
</ol>
<p>When was the last time you wrote a letter? Why not take some time to write a letter to your future self or your family? You can choose email delivery or physical mail delivery (postage at your own expense).</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/02/hqfUyZFOr8pT2cl.webp" alt="Cloud Time Post Office"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://smartynames.com/">Search Domain names with AI</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Describe your company or project in the dialog box, and this AI program will suggest matching domain names.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/03/qEVwyag3XLeK5T9.webp" alt="Search domain names with AI"></p>
<h2 id="documentary"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#documentary"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Documentary</h2>
<p>Today I recommend a documentary called "The Internet's Own Boy." This documentary tells the story of Aaron Swartz, who gave his life for a freer and more open internet.</p>
&#x3C;iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=16549975&#x26;bvid=BV1rx411V75r&#x26;cid=26994578&#x26;page=1&#x26;autoplay=0" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" class="bilibili"> &#x3C;/iframe>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>An Argentine fan fell from an overpass while trying to jump onto a bus carrying the World Cup champion team.</li>
</ol>
&#x3C;iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=692206780&#x26;bvid=BV1Z24y1v7ix&#x26;cid=949017983&#x26;page=1&#x26;autoplay=0" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" class="bilibili"> &#x3C;/iframe>
<blockquote>
<p>That guy originally wanted to see Messi, but he ended up meeting Maradona (the late Argentine football star).</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/03/MJ3pTB2ifegnqxb.webp" alt="Quote image one"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Kim Jong-un welcomes South Korea's Moon Jae-in in Pyongyang</li>
</ol>
&#x3C;iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=31962726&#x26;bvid=BV1NW411C76X&#x26;cid=55906755&#x26;page=1&#x26;autoplay=0" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" class="bilibili"> &#x3C;/iframe>
<blockquote>
<p>I wonder why there are translators beside them when they both speak Korean.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2023/01/03/xyYFH9dkIvr8UmM.webp" alt="Quote image two"></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Past Years #10]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/06/weekly-issue-10</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/06/weekly-issue-10"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Weekly BGM [College Entrance Exam Season Special].</p>
<p>Welcome to the tenth issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "My past years."</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/BrVsEMzPYmdnSF8.jpg" alt="2019 college entrance exam send-off scene at my high school"></p>
&#x3C;center>&#x3C;b>(Cover image: 2019 college entrance exam send-off scene at my high school)&#x3C;/b>&#x3C;/center>
<h2 id="topic-my-past-years"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-my-past-years"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: My Past Years</h2>
<p>The 2022 college entrance exam (Gaokao) has concluded. Every year's exam season inevitably brings back memories of the past, and this year is no exception. On the afternoon of June 6th, I took some time to reminisce about my youth.</p>
<p>That afternoon, I logged into the official websites of my elementary school, middle school, and high school, preparing to download some memorable things for future reminiscence. The results were greatly disappointing – none of my schools' websites could be accessed; they had all gone offline. The information channels for my elementary, middle, and high school had all switched to WeChat official accounts.</p>
<p>I used <a href="https://www.oldestsearch.com/">Oldest Search</a>, which I recommended in issue 6, but still couldn't find historical snapshots of my schools' previous sites.</p>
<p>Eventually, I found historical snapshots of my <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20161024113518/http://hmsyxx.com/">high school site</a>, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20180824200013/http://www.hmnrzx.com/">middle school site</a>, and <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130908231332/http://www.hmdx.net/">elementary school site</a> in the <a href="https://archive.org/">Internet Archive</a>.</p>
<p>My high school's site was last updated in 2016. The historical snapshot matches what I remember seeing when I visited the school website during computer class in my first year of high school. The English listening MP3 files in the "hot articles" list next to the campus news section reminded me of doing listening exercises during morning reading in my freshman year. Back then, the last 20 minutes of every English morning reading session were used for listening practice.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/Pl1N96rTXLHcg5q.png" alt="High school site snapshot"></p>
<p>My middle school's site was last updated in 2018. Every graduating class's graduation video used to be displayed in the left sidebar of the homepage for alumni to reminisce. Since the Internet Archive didn't capture external video links, I couldn't find the 2016 middle school graduation ceremony video – somewhat disappointing. If I visit my alma mater someday in the future, I'll definitely look for that lost footage.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/DZB2xUjLTFr3nt6.png" alt="Middle school site snapshot"></p>
<p>Finding my elementary school's site in the Internet Archive took a long time. Although my memories of elementary school have become blurry over time, I still vividly remember the school's motto – "Let every teacher and student bloom with the smile of success."</p>
<p>Back then, I snatched a "Five Good Student" award from a classmate. Back then, I went with my class to Jianghai Customs Garden for an outing. Back then, during the Lixia egg-fighting festival, I became the egg-fighting champion [actually, I waited for others to fight first before joining – winning through strategy]. Back then, I stood in front of the whole school singing "Shake the Sun"... Everything feels so close, yet so far.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/NVpoIsqtrlmSYdg.png" alt="Elementary school site snapshot"></p>
<p>Once I started the exam-oriented education of middle and high school, my campus life was no longer as rich as in elementary school. The goal in middle school was to study hard and get into a good high school; the goal in high school was to study hard and get into a good university. I loathe this homogenized education – that youth was fulfilling but joyless. In China, the Gaokao is a relatively fair life competition, but fairness cannot mask its homogenization flaws.</p>
<p>Last night [June 8th, 2022], after watching an <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Dg411X7zW">interview</a> with the Jiangsu liberal arts top scorer, I felt more at peace with my Gaokao disappointment. That top scorer eventually went to Wuhan University. Her exceptional performance earned her the top spot, but the excessive pressure unfortunately led to depression.</p>
<p>Between health and grades, I choose health. The meaning of life isn't just about grades, and the meaning of studying isn't just for grades either. During high school, my understanding of computer science was nearly zero. Like most students, I was controlled by my parents for 18 years and was confused about my future.</p>
<p>Since entering the computer science major, I've gradually discovered myself. The new technologies emerging from computer science fascinate me. Learning is no longer exhausting for me – doing what interests me is enjoyable.</p>
<p>But undoubtedly, even in university, there are still courses that waste your life. During my freshman and sophomore years, I was an obedient child, continuing the study methods from high school, eventually achieving a good GPA. In my junior year, I began to awaken. I grew tired of being part of the silent majority, tired of courses that don't teach real skills. I started doing what I like. If I had to choose between failing a course and pursuing my interests, I'd choose my interests. Because failing is just a tactic teachers use to scare the weak. When you're strong enough and teachers know you're pursuing your interests rather than skipping class without reason, they'll respect your choices too.</p>
<p>Watching Bilibili uploader Li Tianyi's <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV17g411R7P1">video</a> was quite touching. Here are some notes I took for your reference. May you find your field of interest early and live for yourself.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/wjx4WrtJAhBX1Fl.png" alt="Notes from watching Li Tianyi&#x27;s video"></p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Take photos when you can, capture moments when you can, show off when you want to. Ten years from now, no camera or photography skill can capture you as you are now. Boldly document life. Every day you have now is worth treasuring.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Most people just drift through life. An excellent person will definitely appear unique.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Replace time spent watching dramas with documentaries, replace time spent scrolling your phone with reading books. Persist for a month and you'll feel obvious progress.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>People are always lonely – learn to adapt. Only inner strength can truly overcome loneliness.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.zkcrush.xyz/">zkcrush</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Secretly tell your crush that you like them. 🫣</p>
<p>Enter your name in the first text box, your crush's name in the second, then click to generate a URL. Share the generated URL with others. If someone enters their name and it matches, it means xxx (figure it out yourself). If it doesn't match, it won't hurt too much. 😄</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/7HPDFYK6I4oepgk.png" alt="zkcrush example image"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.cikeee.com/">CiKe - Movie Calendar</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Recommends an excellent movie every day, solving your movie selection problem. Bookmark it and check when you want to watch a movie during leisure time for inspiration.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/09/20/3UNYRxvgf1dzhic.png" alt="CiKe - Movie Calendar example image"></p>
<h2 id="flag"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#flag"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Flag</h2>
<p>Everything has its nature – water is plain, salt gives flavor. Water plus water is still water, salt plus salt is still salt. Sour, sweet, bitter, spicy, salty – the five flavors harmonized, coexisting and complementing each other, presenting a hundred flavors. Things are like this, events are the same, and so are people.</p>
<p>This was the 2019 Jiangsu Chinese Gaokao essay topic. At that time, I wrote about sour, sweet, bitter, spicy, and salty, and got 97 points in Chinese. If I have time this summer, I'll rewrite the 2019 Jiangsu Chinese Gaokao essay to recapture that year's feeling.</p>
<p>I personally think this is a very cool thing to do. If you also want to reminisce about your Gaokao, you can rewrite your Chinese Gaokao essay when you have time.</p>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Technology First or Tinkering First? #9]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/06/weekly-issue-09</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/06/weekly-issue-09"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Weekly BGM [Dragon Boat Festival Special].</p>
<p>Welcome to the ninth issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "Technology first or tinkering first?"</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/3NoeEwjuitYS7Fa.jpg" alt="Cover image: Coding time"></p>
&#x3C;center>&#x3C;b>(Cover image: Coding time)&#x3C;/b>&#x3C;/center>
<h2 id="international-perspective"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#international-perspective"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>International Perspective</h2>
<p>The latest supercomputer rankings are out, with America's new Frontier supercomputer taking the top spot. See details at <a href="https://www.top500.org/">top500 official website</a></p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/e6Y3bV1yXE97cTC.png" alt="2022 Global Supercomputer Performance Rankings"></p>
<p>The following is a quote from Sina. The US uses its advanced technology and long-arm jurisdiction to hinder Chinese enterprises' development – this behavior is infuriating.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/JuGVyh5cizFsqtQ.png" alt="Sina editorial"></p>
<p>We should never have any illusions about the West and must always maintain crisis awareness. At the same time, we should improve our technical skills and strive to contribute to China's rejuvenation. China's rejuvenation still needs a long time, and breaking free from US technological strangleholds will be difficult in the short term. Let's encourage each other.</p>
<h2 id="topic-technology-first-or-tinkering-first"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-technology-first-or-tinkering-first"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Technology First or Tinkering First?</h2>
<p>Recently, while chatting with a classmate, I found he had lost his initial passion for tinkering and was instead studying Java technology hard. He said he realized his technical skills were currently insufficient and that tinkering with blogs was a waste of time.</p>
<p>At the beginning of this semester, with my guidance, my classmate's WordPress blog was nearly complete, just waiting for him to fill in the content. But after writing 2 Java study notes, he started backing out. He felt that when tired from studying, he just wanted to relax and didn't want to touch the blog at all.</p>
<p>Facing this situation, I fell into deep thought. Should classmates without technical skills tinker at all? During my contemplation, I realized that technology and tinkering are mutually reinforcing – both are important. If I had to choose, I'd choose to tinker first, then learn technology. On one hand, tinkering helps you discover which technical skills you're lacking, helping you clarify your learning goals. On the other hand, learning technology helps you tinker more enjoyably.</p>
<p>Let me use my personal homepage tinkering as an example. Initially, I always liked to use others' pre-made personal homepage templates – cloning open-source projects from GitHub, modifying them, then deploying. The results were indeed good, but one day I realized that since I'm a computer science major, why not build a personal homepage myself?</p>
<p>So I created a new folder and used traditional HTML, CSS, and JS to build my page. After finishing, it looked good on desktop, but as soon as I switched to mobile view in the browser console, the page immediately became distorted.</p>
<p>This made me think. After searching online, I realized that to have good display across multiple devices, I needed responsive layout. Implementing responsive layout with traditional CSS requires strong CSS skills – beyond my current level.</p>
<p>Later, I discovered that frameworks could implement responsive layouts. So I learned a bit about Tailwind CSS, a popular CSS framework, and finally achieved responsive layout for my personal homepage [Note: The personal homepage has been deleted. -2022.11.12]. The code is very short – the framework solved many problems for me.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/xnGLPHqkWwZTVuI.png" alt="Personal homepage source code image"></p>
<p>But during implementation, I also realized my front-end skills were insufficient. So I added some content to my programming goals page in Obsidian – namely, learning React and Vue frameworks.</p>
<p>The above is my experience and insights from tinkering. Tinkering is very valuable – it clarifies what technology you should learn next.</p>
<p>Before, if you didn't know HTML, hand-coding a webpage was inconceivable. Now blog frameworks like Hexo solve this pain point – they can convert your Markdown files to HTML. But if you don't know CSS, your blog styles are limited to what the theme provides, because custom styles require CSS fundamentals. Therefore, learning technology helps us tinker more enjoyably.</p>
<p>In summary, learning technologies that solve problems you encounter while tinkering is a cool thing. Don't forget to tinker while learning technology – constantly ask yourself: Did I use what I learned today? This is what programming learning should look like.</p>
<p>Learning technology without tinkering, or learning without practice, is a major taboo in programming. The result of not practicing is quickly forgetting what you've learned.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Huang Bo said: "Before, in production crews, I always encountered all kinds of people with various schemes. But now (being famous), everyone around me is nice, every face is smiling." People are still the same people; it's just that when you're weak, everyone around is petty – anyone can step on you. When you're strong, the whole world treats you kindly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do the painful tasks first each day, then the easy ones. This way, you'll feel increasingly relaxed. The easy tasks become a reward, giving you more motivation and happiness.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Most people in this world can't distinguish between "their own thoughts" and "thoughts others instilled in them." Life is hard, and blind conformity is a simple and convenient way to gain a sense of belonging, self-worth, and meaning. Thinking is too painful. Giving up independent thinking can only exchange for a comfortable but false life.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Self-discipline isn't about sleeping early, waking early, or eating more vegetables. Self-discipline is always doing only the most important things.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://pinball.flutter.dev/#/">Pinball</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A pinball game released before Google I/O 2022 last month, paying tribute to the classic while showcasing Google's Flutter application development kit.</p>
<p>Note: The space bar charges up power; release to launch. Then use the left arrow key (or A) and right arrow key (or D) to control the flippers below to make the ball bounce multiple times for points. Requires VPN.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/MDpeirhc1Wm5y3w.png" alt="Pinball example image"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://flowus.cn/product">FlowUs</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A newly launched productivity tool, similar to foreign <a href="https://www.notion.so/zh-cn">Notion</a> and domestic <a href="https://www.wolai.com/">Wolai</a>. Can be used to build your own knowledge base or as cloud storage. Those who like to share can use such productivity tools to build personal blogs/homepages. Just fill in the content and click share in the upper right corner.</p>
<p>Ruanyifeng's latest <a href="https://www.ruanyifeng.com/blog/2022/05/weekly-issue-208.html">Tech Enthusiast Weekly</a> has a detailed experience report on FlowUs – click the link to view.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/OZRj2rLf8aXdSFG.png" alt="FlowUs example image"></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://virtualmuseum.intel.com/#">Intel Virtual Museum</a></li>
</ol>
<p>In the virtual museum, you can learn about Intel's history and products through the generations.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/K9UBdAaVtsluiv1.png" alt="Virtual Intel Museum"></p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://privnote.com/">Privnote</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Send private notes that self-destruct after reading. Perfect for encrypted communication or confessing your feelings 😄.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/GDMNB3L7xcoZbzA.png" alt="Privnote example image"></p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://q-link.minung.dev/">Q.Link</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Hide your link behind a quiz. <a href="https://q-link.minung.dev/links/6294cbf624dea1655c28d9f7">Quiz link</a> – after answering correctly, it automatically redirects to the corresponding site after 5 seconds.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/ZdaAD98vpVgUKrx.png" alt="Q.link example image"></p>
<h2 id="tools"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#tools"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Tools</h2>
<p>Recently I watched a <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1i34y177pJ">video</a> by Bilibili uploader Yupi, which was quite touching. He mentioned that doing self-media exercises his sharing and expression abilities. He believes that clearly explaining what you've learned and helping others learn is a very cool thing [this is actually the Feynman learning technique] – this is his initial motivation for continuing to share.</p>
<p>Part of why I write the weekly newsletter is curiosity about newsletters, and part is hoping my sharing can help others. In this issue, I'm starting to recommend some browser extensions I use with good experience, hoping my sharing can help improve your life efficiency.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/smart-toc/lifgeihcfpkmmlfjbailfpfhbahhibba">Smart TOC</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Displays article table of contents, helping you quickly understand the article structure for efficient reading.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/5Y8mwZ6cujJSKDC.png" alt="Smart TOC example image"></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://fanyi.caiyunapp.com/#/web">Caiyun Translator</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Bilingual comparison webpage translation – improves your English reading efficiency while making it easier to accumulate English vocabulary.</p>
<p>Before, I always used Google Chrome's built-in Google Translate to translate English pages. The drawback was that translations became completely disconnected from the original text. Caiyun Translator solves this pain point. Below is my result using Caiyun Translator on an Economist article – translation and original text appear simultaneously.</p>
<p><img src="https://vip2.loli.net/2022/11/12/BzCDFOGK2q7IeiR.png" alt="Caiyun Translator bilingual translation of The Economist"></p>
<h2 id="happy-dragon-boat-festival-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#happy-dragon-boat-festival-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Happy Dragon Boat Festival! 🫔</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Trap of the Information Age—Over-Consuming Content #8]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-08</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-08"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the eighth issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "The trap of the information age—over-consuming content."</p>
<h2 id="gitee-event-sequel"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#gitee-event-sequel"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>🔍Gitee Event Sequel</h2>
<p>This morning while browsing Bilibili, I saw that Gitee's Bilibili account posted a <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1HS4y1q7Do">9th anniversary live recording</a>. Gitee officially responded to the open-source review event that everyone has been concerned about recently. The response to the open-source review event starts at 1 hour 15 minutes and ends around 1 hour 40 minutes in the video. Here are my notes for your reference.</p>
<h2 id="topic-the-trap-of-the-information-ageover-consuming-content"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-the-trap-of-the-information-ageover-consuming-content"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: The Trap of the Information Age—Over-Consuming Content</h2>
<p>In the quotes section of my 6th weekly issue, I cited someone's tweet about "how to become inefficient," which mentioned one point—over-consuming content. Today, I'll use this as a starting point for our discussion.</p>
<p><em>What is over-consuming content?</em></p>
<p>There's no clear definition of this concept online. In my view, over-consuming content means the information you browse daily exceeds your capacity to handle it. The boundary of this capacity is determined by yourself – everyone's capacity is different. Some people might feel eye strain after just 10 minutes on their phone, while others might spend most of their day online. But without a doubt, when information exceeds your capacity, you'll feel exhausted and no longer want to be bombarded by information.</p>
<p>But people with OCD will continue pushing through exhaustion, not stopping until they've seen everything in their feed. This is a typical case of over-consumption. Over-consuming content can also be considered a symptom of internet addiction.</p>
<p>The image below is from an <a href="https://www.addictioncenter.com/drugs/internet-addiction/">article</a> about internet addiction on the addiction center website.</p>
<p>I deeply relate to this point because when I first started creating the weekly newsletter, I was always afraid my content wasn't substantial enough. So I would force myself to scroll through all the updates on various platforms every day.</p>
<p>One night, lying in bed, I chatted with my roommate Leizi next to me. I asked, "Leizi, when you're on TikTok, do you force yourself to scroll through all the updates?" He replied, "Videos on TikTok are endless. Usually I just scroll when I'm relaxing. When I'm tired of scrolling, I stop."</p>
<p>That makes sense. Collecting material for the weekly newsletter is similar to scrolling TikTok. I just need to collect some fresh, interesting things from the internet during my limited relaxation time to share with my readers. When I'm tired of collecting, I can stop.</p>
<p>In this age of information explosion, may you avoid falling into the trap of over-consuming content and fully enjoy the benefits of the internet.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The people you meet in your life basically won't truly like or care about you. Even if you have good feelings or relationships now, it's temporary and won't last a lifetime. Don't have too high expectations for interpersonal relationships, or you'll definitely be disappointed. You must constantly strive for self-improvement. Almost all your interpersonal relationships are built on the premise that "you are valuable to others." Focus your time and energy on becoming stronger, not on pleasing others.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The length of a person's life isn't measured by lifespan but by the richness of experiences. Lying in bed doing nothing but scrolling your phone, a day passes quickly with the feeling of having done nothing – that day was essentially wasted.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<p>In my workflow, I use <a href="https://cubox.pro/">Cubox</a> for collecting materials. I've been using this software since last year, collecting for nearly half a year, and the contents became messy and numerous. On the evening of May 22nd, I spent an entire evening archiving materials I wouldn't use again and tagging materials I might use in the future for easy reference later. Originally, this link sharing section only recommends 2 interesting websites, but because I organized my collection box last Sunday, I'm recommending 5 (3+2) interesting websites this time. The first 3 are carefully selected from my past six months of collection.</p>
<p>You can also try using this material collection software, but it's not suitable for procrastinators – if you don't organize for just one week, your collection box becomes a garbage dump requiring lots of time to clean up. My principle for using this software is to clear it daily.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.timemailer.cn/#/">Time Post Office</a></li>
</ol>
<p>As graduation approaches, why not write a letter to your future self? My college psychology course this semester required writing a letter to my future self. I already submitted my letter on this site in March. I look forward to receiving my March letter next year.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://earthly-tools.com/text-mode?url=">Text Mode</a></li>
</ol>
<p>View web pages in pure text form. Just enter the website address you want to view after <code>url=</code> in the address bar.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://www.pawmenow.com/what-dogs-can-eat/">What Human Foods are Healthy for Dogs to Eat?</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A site to determine which human foods are healthy for dogs. For example, when I entered "rice," the following prompt appeared.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><a href="https://emojied.net/">emojied</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Shorten your links using emojis. For example, my personal blog link is <code>https://jiakai.page</code>. After conversion through this site, it becomes <code>https://emojied.net/😉🙃😌😨😍😰</code>.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><a href="https://batnoter.com/">batnoter</a></li>
</ol>
<p>An open-source, Markdown-based, self-hosted-to-GitHub note-taking web application. You can use it as your own random notebook. [Note: This app was originally called gitnoter, later renamed to batnoter]</p>
<p>After saving notes, they automatically sync to your GitHub repository.</p>
<p>When I'm not busy, I use this software to record interesting and fresh things I encounter. When I'm busy, I still use Cubox to save interesting and fresh things, then organize them when I have free time.</p>
<h2 id="fun-facts"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#fun-facts"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Fun Facts</h2>
<ol>
<li>An interesting Truth from Trump.</li>
</ol>
<p>Translation:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I collected billions of dollars from South Korea to make them, a very wealthy country, pay something for their military protection. Biden just walked away, asking for nothing. They think we're too stupid.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Is Very Un-Open-Source #7]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-07</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-07"/>
        <updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the seventh issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "This is very un-open-source."</p>
<h2 id="topic-this-is-very-un-open-source"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-this-is-very-un-open-source"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: This Is Very Un-Open-Source</h2>
<p>The above is Gitee's official response to the measure requiring review before open-source repositories go live. Regarding this, I'm deeply disappointed.</p>
<p>Gitee was forced into this. The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology requires platforms to be responsible for all content on their platforms, so Gitee's management came up with this terrible measure.</p>
<p>The image hosting ban at the end of March, and the repository review-before-going-live policy at the end of May – this series of moves by Gitee has once again lowered my trust in domestic brands.</p>
<p>Bilibili uploader "Monkey King" made a satirical video specifically for this – <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV16R4y1c7sf">What if programmers had to go to a business hall for open-source review</a>. 😄😄😄</p>
<p>Gitee's measure was mocked by netizens as "no open-source unless necessary" 😅. Saying more is useless – after all, this is just my personal opinion. Everyone has their own unique perspective. I hope readers of my words can think independently and make their own judgments.</p>
<p>For more responses, see the discussion of this issue on Zhihu: <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/533388365">How do you view the May 18th Gitee requirement that repositories must be reviewed before being open-sourced, with some already open-sourced repositories temporarily closed until they pass review?</a></p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Looks determine whether things can start; personality determines whether things can last.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The stages a programmer goes through:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Work hard to learn technology</li>
<li>Use technology to gain influence</li>
<li>Use influence to earn 💰</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://lofifm.vercel.app/">lofifm</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Another free lofi music site. You can put on headphones while studying and use it as white noise, adding a touch of fun to boring study sessions.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://github.com/chubin/wttr.in">Check weather via command line</a></li>
</ol>
<pre class="language-powershell"><code class="language-powershell code-highlight"><span class="code-line"><span class="token comment"># Check weather in Nanjing</span>
</span><span class="code-line">curl wttr<span class="token punctuation">.</span>in/Nanjing
</span><span class="code-line"><span class="token comment"># Check weather in Haimen District, Nantong</span>
</span><span class="code-line">curl wttr<span class="token punctuation">.</span>in/Haimen
</span><span class="code-line"><span class="token comment"># Check weather in Zhumadian, Henan</span>
</span><span class="code-line">curl wttr<span class="token punctuation">.</span>in/Zhumadian
</span><span class="code-line"><span class="token comment"># Check weather in Wuxi</span>
</span><span class="code-line">curl wttr<span class="token punctuation">.</span>in/Wuxi
</span></code></pre>
<p>Of course, the prerequisite for entering these commands is having curl installed on your computer. You can search for specific installation methods yourself.</p>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have You Achieved Music Freedom? #6]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-06</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-06"/>
        <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the sixth issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "Have you achieved music freedom?"</p>
<h2 id="topic-have-you-achieved-music-freedom"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-have-you-achieved-music-freedom"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Have You Achieved Music Freedom?</h2>
<p>I'm sure you've encountered situations where you have to pay to listen to music. Domestic music giant QQ Music has gone so far as to mark all of Jay Chou's classic songs as VIP-exclusive – they'll do anything for money. 😮‍💨 Jay Chou is a leading figure in Chinese pop music. Just imagine how many fans in mainland China would pay for membership just to listen to his songs.</p>
<p>QQ Music is the vendor with the most music copyrights in mainland China, but their money-grabbing behavior based on their abundant resources disgusts me. [Last month, I had a momentary lapse of judgment and got a QQ Music membership just to listen to a song called "Star Moon Candy." <del>I probably won't renew it</del>. <strong>QQ Music is the largest local music platform, and among all music platforms, it offers the best support for Chinese songs. If there's a need, I'll definitely renew!</strong> (Added on 2022.11.12)]</p>
<p>NetEase Cloud Music also has songs that require VIP to listen to...</p>
<p>Music is similar to software – open source has benefits but also drawbacks. For music, if users can listen and download for free, users achieve "music freedom"; but this approach harms music creators' interests and may dampen their creative enthusiasm. For software, if the source code is open, software update iterations speed up, but it may also cause original authors to abandon projects because they can't profit.</p>
<p>I support the music vendor operating model of free listening with paid downloads. The platform takes a small portion of profits, with the rest going to music creators. But I firmly oppose the money-grabbing behavior mentioned above [QQ Music marking almost all of Jay Chou's classic songs as VIP-exclusive].</p>
<p>On foreign platform Spotify, Jay Chou's songs are completely free. Domestic Migu Music also makes almost all Jay Chou songs freely available. Only QQ Music in China is raking in money based on copyrights – I can't stand this behavior.</p>
<p>The comments above reflect Chinese people's inner feelings, but they also reveal the current situation of insufficient copyright awareness among Chinese people. When freeloading becomes a habit, it means repeatedly plundering creators' work. Remember to freeload in moderation – don't treat freeloading as something taken for granted!</p>
<p>This Zhihu answer fully illustrates the current state of the music market. Major music vendors are fighting against each other under the banner of copyright protection for their own interests. <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/320564099/answer/1634954859">How do you view paying for music?</a></p>
<p>True music freedom doesn't exist – the fact that musicians also need to eat makes it impractical. I hope that while protecting copyrights in the future, capitalists will also restrain their money-grabbing tendencies. Only then will Chinese people be willing to pay for good music.</p>
<p>GitHub is paradise for open-source software, SciHub is paradise for academic papers – is there a music paradise? With an exploratory mindset, I discovered <a href="https://www.music-hub.com/">MusicHub</a> online, but it's not a music paradise – it's a site that provides convenience for musicians to publish their work.</p>
<p>I checked some related domain names for musichub. Good domain names were registered long ago, but musichub.com isn't active. Good domain names being hoarded is a tragedy of our times, but what can we do? My birth timing meant I missed the domain name boom.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>How to become inefficient?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Sit indoors all day</li>
<li>Don't exercise</li>
<li>Over-consume content</li>
<li>Keep your phone next to your desk while working</li>
</ul>
<ol start="2">
<li>Everyone talks about GPA rankings, national first-class and second-class honors. No one loves knowledge anymore, no one wants to understand problems anymore. Every effort must be resume-worthy, otherwise it's worthless.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://andisearch.com/">Andi</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Andi is a next-generation search engine – bringing you a conversational, anonymous, and ad-free search experience. Andi gives you direct answers to complex questions. It also fights spam and protects you from ad tech.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.oldestsearch.com/">Oldest Search</a></li>
</ol>
<p>The oldest search engine.</p>
<p>All results are page snapshots captured 10 years ago.</p>
<h2 id="rest-early-for-tomorrows-workday-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#rest-early-for-tomorrows-workday-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Rest early for tomorrow's workday. 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Efficiently Prepare for Graduate School Exams? #5]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-05</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/05/weekly-issue-05"/>
        <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the fifth issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "How to efficiently prepare for graduate school entrance exams?"</p>
<h2 id="topic-how-to-efficiently-prepare-for-graduate-school-exams"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-how-to-efficiently-prepare-for-graduate-school-exams"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: How to Efficiently Prepare for Graduate School Exams?</h2>
<p>Recently, I found myself becoming increasingly lost while doing practice problems for the graduate school entrance exam math section. The further I progressed, the more problems I couldn't solve.</p>
<p>The reasons for not being able to solve problems come down to two things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increased difficulty of problems</li>
<li>Weak foundation</li>
</ul>
<p>Last night, I stopped doing new practice problems and started reviewing the problems I had gotten wrong before. I also asked a high-achieving senior for advice.</p>
<p>Here are the senior's preparation tips. I also asked which problem set he was using. He said he hasn't started doing practice problems yet and is still solidifying his foundation. His progress: only probability theory left in math, while my progress: calculus up to definite integrals, with linear algebra and probability theory not yet started. I felt anxious and resolved to speed up my review pace starting tomorrow. Here's the advice the senior gave me.</p>
<p>But don't rush things too much either. Maintain your own pace and don't be influenced by others. Just because the senior is progressing faster doesn't mean I should rush through everything trying to catch up to his speed. Just make sure each day of review is fulfilling and you have no regrets.</p>
<p>During my conversation with the senior, I learned that he has a habit of exercising daily. I've neglected exercise for almost a year now – ever since the 2400-meter physical education test in my sophomore year, I haven't pushed myself to exercise consistently.</p>
<p>Exercise isn't my hobby. I used to treat it as leverage for high PE scores; now I view it as a way to release stress. As long as it's not raining, I aim to run 1000 meters every day. I wonder if you, the reader, have a habit of exercising daily. If not, try persisting for 21 days to make it a habit. You'll release stress while building a foundation for your health.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>What we really want is more freedom for speech that benefits our interests, while hoping for less freedom for speech that doesn't benefit us. <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1mr4y1b7xM">via</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Why waste time when you meet the right person? <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Ku411v7GS">via</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://qwerty.cooleryue.cn/">Qwerty Learner</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Software designed for keyboard workers to memorize vocabulary and train English typing skills. It exercises both your typing ability and vocabulary – two birds with one stone. 😄</p>
<p>(My data from one round of vocabulary practice)</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.similarsites.com/">Similar Sites</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A website that helps you find "similar websites." For example, when I entered "4399.com" in the search box, the site listed many websites similar to 4399 Mini Games, with 7k7k Mini Games having the highest similarity.</p>
<p>✍️ I originally wanted to completely abandon the weekly newsletter and focus solely on exam preparation. But after thinking about it, I decided to continue with this issue. Since I spend about ten hours a day in the study room, I have plenty of time. Squeezing out 2-3 hours a week to complete the newsletter is more than enough.</p>
<p>✨ I believe in my efficiency, and I firmly believe that persisting with newsletter writing will make me fall in love with writing over time. Years from now, when I look back at my immature words, I think I'll be moved by my former self.</p>
<h2 id="have-a-great-monday-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-monday-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great Monday! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are You Being Trapped in a Filter Bubble? #4]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-04</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-04"/>
        <updated>2022-04-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the fourth issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "Are you being trapped in a filter bubble?"</p>
&#x3C;center>&#x3C;b>Cover image: Filter Bubble&#x3C;/b>&#x3C;/center>
<h2 id="topic-are-you-being-trapped-in-a-filter-bubble"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-are-you-being-trapped-in-a-filter-bubble"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Are You Being Trapped in a Filter Bubble?</h2>
<p><em>What is a filter bubble (information cocoon)?</em></p>
<p>If you keep browsing content about a single topic on platforms like TikTok or Bilibili, your homepage recommendations will soon be flooded with videos about that topic. I'm sure you've experienced this. The logic behind it is the recommendation algorithm at work, similar to Taobao's "Guess What You Like" feature.</p>
<p>My attitude toward this is neutral. On one hand, these recommendations sometimes save me time finding similar videos, and they also give content creators traffic boosts, increasing their exposure. On the other hand, I sometimes resent it because these recommendations accelerate my aesthetic fatigue. At the same time, they reduce my chances of discovering interesting new information – the recommendation algorithm encloses me within a certain domain. I feel like a silkworm, wrapped up in a cocoon made by technology.</p>
<p>Letting recommendation algorithms create a cocoon around you is dangerous. It narrows your vision, making you immersed in areas you're interested in while knowing little about other fields. Although in the internet age, with search engines at our disposal, we don't need to become polymaths – we can solve most problems by asking search engines. But learning about other fields is never a bad thing.</p>
<p>How can we avoid being trapped in a filter bubble?</p>
<ul>
<li>Actively train the recommendation algorithm</li>
</ul>
<p>We can use the characteristics of recommendation algorithms to our advantage by browsing videos from different fields that interest us. This way, when the algorithm makes recommendations, it has more options to choose from. Actively training the recommendation algorithm requires you to change your self-positioning. Although the algorithm recommends information to you passively, this recommendation is based on your active training, making your acceptance pseudo-passive.</p>
<ul>
<li>Actively seek information</li>
</ul>
<p>In your spare time, follow blogs, official accounts, and newsletters from internet experts. Their writings may occasionally recommend interesting new things, and you can follow their guidance to continue searching until you feel there's no need to continue – similar to depth-first traversal in data structures.</p>
<p>For example, sometimes based on a blogger's hyperlink, I'll go to a GitHub repository and briefly look at the repository description. If I think the project is great, I'll give it a star. Then I'll check out the repository owner's GitHub profile, and if there's a link to their personal website, I'll click through to explore... In short, stop searching when you feel it's time to end.</p>
<p>The following is a quote I read in a newsletter that resonated with me. In summary, whether actively training the recommendation algorithm or actively seeking information, the key word is "active" – avoiding filter bubbles effectively requires you to be proactive rather than completely passively accepting algorithm recommendations.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Interest is the best teacher. If you don't have interest, cultivate it; otherwise, don't enter this industry.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Small habits make it easier for us to persist and build confidence in ourselves.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Work hard to change what can be changed; peacefully accept what you're powerless to change.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://nsfwjs.com/">nsfwjs</a></li>
</ol>
<p><em>What is NSFW?</em></p>
<p>The above site can identify inappropriate images. I heard from friends in a Telegram group that this site cannot accurately identify pornographic images related to anime characters.</p>
<p>The image below shows my test of the site using a photo of a foreign beauty. The pornographic rating was 0.08%. Feel free to test your treasured beauty photos for their pornographic rating. 😄😄😄</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://findtheinvisiblecow.com/">Find the Invisible Cow</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A fun browser game where a cow hides on the screen. The closer your mouse gets to the cow, the louder its sound becomes. Hint: The mouse cursor will eventually change shape. 👆</p>
<p>Click again to find the hidden cow. 🐮</p>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say No to Homogenization #3]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-03</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-03"/>
        <updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the third issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "Say no to homogenization."</p>
<h2 id="topic-reject-homogenization"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-reject-homogenization"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Reject Homogenization</h2>
<p><em>What is homogenization?</em></p>
<p>Before entering university, I always heard rumors that once in college, I could freely choose my courses and have more options. But after entering university, I found reality was different. My schedule was still filled with courses I didn't like, and because I didn't like them, I had little motivation to study.</p>
<p>This week, I read a blog post titled <a href="http://huangxuan.me/2021/01/19/the-systematic-failure-of-higher-education-in-china/"><em>The Systematic Failure of Higher Education in China</em></a>. This article is the author's response to a <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/439622084/answer/1685314467">question</a> on Zhihu.</p>
<p>After reading it, I was deeply moved. Regarding "<strong>the score-only mentality and homogenized education before entering university</strong>," I personally relate to this. High scores in middle and high school only prove that you put in effort; they don't mean much else. The streaming system after middle school exams separates Chinese students into different levels too early, causing the gap to widen further, with struggling students falling further behind.</p>
<p>Excellence isn't measured by scores but by actual ability – that is, how much you can contribute to society. Last summer, I accidentally clicked on a <a href="https://www.dandyweng.com/">blogger's website</a> and was amazed. The amazement wasn't because the blog was flashy, but because the blogger built it himself without using any existing framework.</p>
<p>This blogger, named Weng Tianxin, is self-taught and has never attended a single day of school. He only acquires knowledge that interests him from nature and the internet. Completely separating from the conventional education system doesn't mean he's rebellious; rather, it has allowed him to understand himself and become the person he wants to be.</p>
<p>The image below shows a quote I saw in his blog's comment section. Sometimes, going against convention doesn't necessarily lead you to the opposite side of the world; instead, it might help you live a more exciting life than ordinary people.</p>
<p>Looking back at the conventional path we've taken, homogenized education has blurred our goals. In a homogenized educational environment, we don't clearly know what we want, what kind of person we want to become, or what role we want to play in society.</p>
<p>I only awakened during my junior year's first semester, realizing that I want to become a programmer in the future. If you're still in a state of confusion, why not stop and think about your aspirations? Set your goals early and work hard toward them. Don't waste any more time in university classrooms that just follow the textbook.</p>
<p>If China continues with this homogenized education in the future, I'll consider personally teaching my children. I'll help them master self-learning abilities early, learn knowledge that interests them on their own, and become the people they want to be. I won't let them be assimilated by homogenized education.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The greatest value of elite schools lies not in educational quality but in providing students with more opportunities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The conventional path is conventional because it suits most people.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://matching.name/">Matching.name</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Enter keywords in the search box and it will generate the most suitable domain name for you. For example, when I entered my name, it recommended a .ai domain suffix.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://www.autopiano.cn/">Free Piano</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Online piano, keyboard piano, simulated piano, with multiple instrument options – fun to listen to and fun to play. For a piano novice like me, I just choose to listen to the performance examples, like this JJ Lin's <a href="https://www.autopiano.cn/midi/46812212798731"><em>Jiangnan</em></a>.</p>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have You Experienced SEO Pollution? #2]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-02</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-02"/>
        <updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the second issue of "Weekly Insights." This week's topic is "Have you experienced SEO pollution?"</p>
<h2 id="topic-have-you-experienced-seo-pollution"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-have-you-experienced-seo-pollution"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: Have You Experienced SEO Pollution?</h2>
<p>SEO pollution contaminates the internet just like garbage pollutes the environment.</p>
<p>First, let me explain what SEO pollution is. The following definition is from Baidu Encyclopedia.</p>
<p>A few days ago, I came across a Zhihu topic recommended by other bloggers: <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/49684783/answer/2305132342">Is the output of the Chinese internet gradually withering?</a></p>
<p>After reading others' responses, I deeply resonated with them. Especially as a computer science student like me, when I encounter problems and ask search engines, the results are often filled with unbearable garbage. Sites like "Programmer Baby" and "Programmer Base" that scrape content are truly disgusting.</p>
<p>Take an article I published on Blog Garden about <a href="http://www.manongjc.com/detail/29-zexdztdpcwouzfc.html">Gitee image hosting being banned</a> [the original has been completely deleted; you can see the scraper site's backup] – I was one of the first bloggers to publish related articles. The day after I posted it, when I searched for my article on various search engines, I found that scraper sites had already collected my article 😅.</p>
<p>These scraper sites aggregate all kinds of blog posts, but this type of aggregation is meaningless. To put it bluntly, it's just a garbage site collecting garbage.</p>
<p>This is what netizens think of CSDN. I've seen this type of blog post – although the hyperlink might eventually solve my problem, I have no gratitude toward the blogger who provided the hyperlink. I'm only grateful to the original author. CSDN is a garbage site. Although it may contain some quality articles from bloggers, overall the blog quality is low. This is one reason I left CSDN.</p>
<p>Fed up with the search experience polluted by SEO, how can we break through?</p>
<p>Last December, I discovered <a href="https://github.com/iorate/ublacklist">ublacklist</a> and <a href="https://github.com/eallion/uBlacklist-subscription-compilation">uBlacklist subscription compilation</a>. It can block specific websites from appearing in Google and Bing search results – just follow the simple configuration in the GitHub repository's README. Since Baidu search engine results are mostly garbage anyway, I don't plan to explore methods for blocking specific sites from Baidu search results. For users in mainland China, I recommend using Bing search; if possible, use Google search.</p>
<h2 id="quotes"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quotes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Quotes</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Writing is our external scaffolding; writing itself is thinking. <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV16T4y197ka">via</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The following is a quote from the movie "The Wandering Earth." Looking at it now, how fitting it is for our current situation. COVID-19 has ravaged us for three years and continues to do so – this is a disaster. But we cannot be pessimistic because of COVID; we must continue to love life as always.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>At first, no one cared about this disaster. It was just a wildfire, a drought, the extinction of a species, the disappearance of a city – until this disaster became closely related to everyone.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://spacecraft.vercel.app/">Spacecraft</a></li>
</ol>
<p>A browser-based shooting game worth playing.</p>
<p>After accumulating enough energy, you can press Enter to fire a super wave. 😄</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="https://cloud.niucodata.com/">Word Cloud Tool</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Generate word cloud images based on input text.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><a href="https://music.163.com/outchain/player?type=2&#x26;id=5276810"><em>A Maiden's Prayer</em></a> – A pure and beautiful piano piece. Sharing it with you, may your soul stay forever young in this noisy world.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Are Billionaires Made? #1]]></title>
        <id>https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-01</id>
        <link href="https://gujiakai.top/en/2022/04/weekly-issue-01"/>
        <updated>2022-04-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello 👋, friend. Starting today, I've decided to write a weekly newsletter sharing what I've seen and heard over the past week.</p>
<h2 id="topic-how-are-billionaires-made"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#topic-how-are-billionaires-made"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Topic: How Are Billionaires Made?</h2>
<p>Elon Musk acquired 9.2% of Twitter's shares, becoming the company's largest shareholder. Looking at the Forbes billionaire list with Musk at the top, I couldn't help but wonder: why is this man so successful?</p>
<p>After researching online, I've summarized the following factors that contributed to his success:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hard work</li>
<li>Innovative spirit</li>
<li>Foresight</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, there are many more factors that contributed to his success. In this issue, I'll only discuss three perspectives.</p>
<p>First, hard work is an essential component of success. Slacking off at work and letting your mind wander reduces efficiency, which extends the path to success. Life has only a few critical moments, and if you don't do the right things at the right time, you're destined not to succeed.</p>
<p>I've never seen anyone enjoy the fruits of success without putting in effort. Wang Sicong, son of Wang Jianlin and a "rich second generation," has actually mastered considerable computer knowledge. If you're interested, you can search for "Dianwan Tech" on Bilibili or YouTube – there are several videos about building servers for Wang Sicong. The information revealed in these videos shows that Wang Sicong is not an uneducated idler; he has studied relevant knowledge diligently. Although his success largely depends on his father's wealth, he continues to create new value based on the foundation of inherited wealth.</p>
<p>Technologies like autonomous driving and batteries are all manifestations of Musk's innovative spirit. Although he didn't implement these himself, he initiated their development. It's his pursuit of innovation that gives him innovative awareness.</p>
<p>In his 200th weekly newsletter <a href="https://www.ruanyifeng.com/blog/2022/03/weekly-issue-200.html"><em>Low Expectations, More Attempts</em></a>, Ruanyifeng wrote: "We should be as cautious as Munger and as action-oriented as Musk." Munger is the vice chairman of an American investment holding company, known for being cautious and never playing cards he's unsure about. Musk, on the other hand, dares to challenge the unknown. He believed electric vehicles would be the future. As it turns out, electric vehicles align perfectly with today's environmental and green themes, and Tesla's success brought Musk to the peak of his career.</p>
<h2 id="link-sharing"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#link-sharing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Link Sharing</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><a href="https://focus-sounds.vercel.app/">Focus Sound</a> – A site hosted on Vercel with many sounds to choose from. You can open it while studying to enhance your learning atmosphere.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.thiswebsitewillselfdestruct.com/">The Self-Destructing Website</a> – A place to write down your feelings. If no new messages are received within 24 hours, the site will disappear. Tencent Cloud's official <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1J3411J7Ym">video</a> on Bilibili describes this in detail.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="have-a-great-weekend-"><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#have-a-great-weekend-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a>Have a great weekend! 😆</h2>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>